<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xml" href="zaza.studio/zazathebassist.github.io/feed.xslt.xml"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.2.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="zaza.studio/zazathebassist.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="zaza.studio/zazathebassist.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-12-29T13:42:22-08:00</updated><id>zaza.studio/zazathebassist.github.io/</id><title type="html">Project Incomplete</title><subtitle>Emmanuel Medina's Personal Blog, Portfolio, and page to mess around</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Accidental Disconnect from the Internet</title><link href="zaza.studio/zazathebassist.github.io/blog/accidental-disconnect/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Accidental Disconnect from the Internet" /><published>2018-12-28T23:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2018-12-28T23:00:00-08:00</updated><id>zaza.studio/zazathebassist.github.io/blog/accidental-disconnect</id><content type="html" xml:base="zaza.studio/zazathebassist.github.io/blog/accidental-disconnect/">&lt;p&gt;It’s been an odd month or two for me. For the first time in as long as I can remember, I’ve been mostly disconnected from the internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This wasn’t really any kind of planned event. I had recently become more active on the Do By Friday discord, was fairly active with my bands social media, rediscovered Twitter a third time, and was actually enjoying Instagram. Then, shortly before I took my trip to Mexico, my use basically plummited. Mexico certainly helped, I ran out of data shortly after my plane arrived and I had basically nothing but simple texting for a week. But even after that, my usage of almost all social media went down to near zero.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been thinking about my internet usage for a while. It definitely was something on my mind since I took a trip to Yosemite in April because, turns out, there’s almost no cell signals, and I felt &lt;em&gt;fine&lt;/em&gt;. I didn’t feel like I was missing out in anything, or like I would fall apart if something happened online and I didn’t come across it. But the moment I got back into society, I went back on my phone. I got a new laptop, went to WWDC, got involved in multiple online communities, hell met my SO online. But I had this feeling that I needed to get away from it all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was not made easier by CGP Grey releasing a lot of content relating to his sabbatical from the internet. It framed the internet as a bad thing that is affecting his focus, and it kind of made me uncomfortable how it brought into focus my relationship with the internet. But I was in denial. Grey is dumb, it’s not the internet’s fault, it’s how his brain works, or it’s actually x or y, or he remembers the past wrong and was always like this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt; Then, I kinda just disconnected from the internet... and he was right. And I felt like a slightly better person while doing it. &lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It gave me a good chance to reflect on what the Internet was really doing to me. I don’t believe that it is affecting my attention like other do, that comes from elsewhere. But it definitely was affecting my sanity, because right before my disconnect, were the 2018 Midterm Elections. Elections whose news stories I tracked, whose stats I watched, whose follow up I kept such a close eye on to see which races flipped where at what points due to mail in ballots or issues with voting or otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I went from that, to a period where I had almost no political news. Almost no news whatsoever actually. I felt &lt;em&gt;free&lt;/em&gt;. But the terrible part is that I felt free &lt;em&gt;after&lt;/em&gt; I realized and started reconnecting. &lt;em&gt;After&lt;/em&gt; I started refollowing tech sites, political sites, started getting back on Reddit and Twitter, I realized how much those sites impacted me. How sad and stressed they truly made me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I’m left with a dilemma. What am I to do. What could I possibly do to take care of myself. The solution I think I landed on is, sadly, “more technology.” I have picked up a calendar and task manager app(I’ll write about those later) to help me focus on what I &lt;em&gt;have&lt;/em&gt; to do instead of what I &lt;em&gt;want to&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;shouldn’t&lt;/em&gt; do online. I’ve started just browsing news sites on my PC but saving interesting articles to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instapaper.com/&quot;&gt;Instapaper&lt;/a&gt; so I could read the actual articles in a well designed, clutter free location so I can only focus on one thing. I am thinking about something like an Apple Watch so I can segment notifications into things I need to see on the Watch and things I can ignore on the phone. I’ve turned off basically every notification on my phone minus calls, texts, and Omnifocus(this included getting rid of email notifications, that 30,000+ red bubble). I’m considering an iPad for purely writing and reading web articles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a lot to think about. I have some travel in Mid-January that will force another short disconnect from the internet. So I’m going to see how much that affects me. But I’m sure that I’ll be back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mean… I just started a blog that I’m actually keeping up kinda sorta just a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn’t the end of my experiment. But I will definitely be something I think about a LOT in the coming year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wf2VxeIm1no&quot;&gt;CGP Grey’s Disconnect YouTube Video&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.relay.fm/cortex/74&quot;&gt;Disconnect Discussion on Cortex&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">It’s been an odd month or two for me. For the first time in as long as I can remember, I’ve been mostly disconnected from the internet.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Coming Back to Magic</title><link href="zaza.studio/zazathebassist.github.io/blog/coming-back-to-magic/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Coming Back to Magic" /><published>2018-12-04T23:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2018-12-04T23:00:00-08:00</updated><id>zaza.studio/zazathebassist.github.io/blog/coming-back-to-magic</id><content type="html" xml:base="zaza.studio/zazathebassist.github.io/blog/coming-back-to-magic/">&lt;p&gt;I left Magic about two years ago. It was a slow fade, and once I was done I thought I was out. I thought I quit this Cardboard Crack&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OH NO&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You &lt;em&gt;don’t&lt;/em&gt; just leave Magic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I’m &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;so glad&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; I’m back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Backstory. I stopped playing Magic about two years ago mostly due to money and time. I couldn’t justify the entry fee, or the time commitment every Friday. So I stopped going. I still kept up with some news, but without playing, that slowed down too. I couldn’t play Magic Online, because that is a steaming pile of garbage(more on that later) and Magic stopped being a part of my life. And when I finally wanted to get back into it, my LGS shut down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was deep into Magic. Like… deep in the competitive circle. My LGS was one of the most competitive stores in all SoCal. And with it shutting down, I felt like even if I wanted to start again, I couldn’t. Most other LGSs in my area(which were still 30 minute drive from me) were really casual, and none of the people I had become friends with went to them. And the nearest “competitive” store, where most of the players moved to, was an hours drive away. I did not have a chance to get back into Magic even if I wanted to. A local GP passed and I didn’t go. I would go to every major event in SoCal beforehand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then came Magic Arena.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Image3_Izzet.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MTGA_Gameplay&quot; title=&quot;Magic Arena is Beautiful&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Magic Arena is a brand new client designed by Wizards of the Coast to play Magic online. Magic Arena is also currently in Open Beta, but I’ve been playing since the closed beta. And it has revived in me a love of Magic I thought I lost a while ago. The other online offerings were bad. So I touched no online way to play Magic until Arena. And Arena is something else. I was skeptical at first, because the last attempt was really bad(people are still crying about MTGO v4). But boy was I wrong. The experience is smooth, the gameplay exceptional, it has a very Apple-like sense of &lt;em&gt;Discoverability&lt;/em&gt; where features you don’t need will be barely hidden, but when you finally need it they’ll be out in the open. It is &lt;em&gt;full Magic&lt;/em&gt; with all the insane rule complexities of Magic, but with a design and interface that is stellar for both new players and veterans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But all this is just praising the client itself, what I really am here to do is talk about how it helped me rediscover a love I thought I lost. I had tried, in the time I was away from Magic, to fill that void. I played Hearthstone religiously for a few months. But it lacked a depth that Magic had. I tried MTGO, but the economy is a direct mirror of paper MTG for absolutely no reason and the actual program looks like it’s written for Windows 95, and has stability to match. But here was a version of Magic that captured everything that made paper Magic so wonderful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Magic is a game I will praise until the end of time. It is so well designed, and the R&amp;amp;D Team at Wizards really does their best to make sure it is still relevant. In the 25 years it has been around, the power creep has been so well managed that eternal decks will still play cards printed 20+ years ago, along with cards made today. And you can feel it. Magic is a game you can teach any kid old enough to logic and you can have a casual game with, but is also deep enough to evoke 20+ years of game theory on, and still have emerging thoughts even today. No other game, at least that I’ve found, has that. It is a game that massive communities have built around, a game that continues to gain fans. And Arena is the first time a program has captured this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is still early on. It is a Beta after all. Simple things like friends lists are still being worked on, and actual tournaments seem a ways away. &lt;del&gt;Plus no Mac client yet grumble grumble&lt;/del&gt;. But I just wanted to sing praises to the game that got me back into Magic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;Image Courtesy of Wizards of the Coast&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">I left Magic about two years ago. It was a slow fade, and once I was done I thought I was out. I thought I quit this Cardboard Crack</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Back to Living in Fear</title><link href="zaza.studio/zazathebassist.github.io/blog/back-in-fear/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Back to Living in Fear" /><published>2018-11-22T23:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2018-11-22T23:00:00-08:00</updated><id>zaza.studio/zazathebassist.github.io/blog/back-in-fear</id><content type="html" xml:base="zaza.studio/zazathebassist.github.io/blog/back-in-fear/">&lt;p&gt;When I was a kid, I had one big fear. Most kids were scared of heights, or the dark, or the monster under the bed. I was scared of being pulled over. I was scared that the cops were going to take away my mom and dad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a child of immigrants. I wont go into it too much, but I’ll just say both my parents are citizens now. They weren’t then. I would get bouts of anxiety if my dad took too long to get home. Did they finally pull him over? Did he run into an immigration checkpoint(they were common in California). Is tonight the night I lose my dad? This was a time before cell phones were common, so I was doubly paranoid. But time passes. Those checkpoints became less common, and my parents went through the process to naturalize.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why am I writing about this now. Why am I talking about a childhood fear? Because today, on Thanksgiving day when I’m writing this, that fear came back. That fear that started lingering in the back of my mind since November 2016 came back full force. But this time, it’s me, and I’m scared if I’ll ever make it home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, writing this, on Thanksgiving Day 2018, Donald Trump, in a fit of imbecilic rage, announced that he is authorizing the use of force on the Mexican border, and is considering outright closing it. Also, today on Thanksgiving Day, I am in Mexico, on the other side of the Mexican border, with plane tickets to go back in a few days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt; &quot;Earlier on Thursday, U.S. President Donald Trump said he had authorized the use of lethal force on the border and warned that the United States could close the whole frontier.&quot; - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/article/us-usa-immigration-caravan/tensions-rise-at-u-s-mexico-border-as-migrants-holiday-travelers-wait-to-cross-idUSKCN1NS01A&quot;&gt;Reuters&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is everything I feared. It is the reality of so many people, that our President, someone elected who &lt;em&gt;lost the popular vote&lt;/em&gt; could make one decision and ruin so many lives. But worse, it pulls me back to that kid, home from school, worried that his dad won’t come home tonight. Or who sees flashing police lights up ahead and wonders if it will be my last day in the US.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t know why I’m writing this. I don’t have a point. Trump is in office for two more years. If they truly close the border there’s other legal ways for American Citizens to enter the country. I would be thrown into a financial hole if that happens, but life would go on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I needed this off my chest. I needed to vent. To scream. To &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;FUCKING SCREAM&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. Because today, I saw my life disappear. In one rash string of tweets, on the day where Americans are supposed to be celebrating the hospitality the natives showed what was ostensively a group of immigrants, one statement threw me into a panic attack. One statement made me cry. And I’m filled with pure hopelessness, because I know it won’t be the last time.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">When I was a kid, I had one big fear. Most kids were scared of heights, or the dark, or the monster under the bed. I was scared of being pulled over. I was scared that the cops were going to take away my mom and dad.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Test Blog Part 3!</title><link href="zaza.studio/zazathebassist.github.io/blog/test-blog-part-3/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Test Blog Part 3!" /><published>2018-11-21T01:39:53-08:00</published><updated>2018-11-21T01:39:53-08:00</updated><id>zaza.studio/zazathebassist.github.io/blog/test-blog-part-3</id><content type="html" xml:base="zaza.studio/zazathebassist.github.io/blog/test-blog-part-3/">&lt;blockquote&gt; I've had two blogs, and abandoned both. So... I'm launching my third blog... What am I Doing Here. &lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Blog-text.png&quot; alt=&quot;Side note, Atom is a fantastic text editor&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ask myself that all too much. This is the 3rd blog I try(4th if you count tumblr… I don’t) in earnest to start. And it’s been up in some capacity since September, without updates, so even before I get it in a decent state I already feel like I failed(I talk more about my view on failure Here). But here I am. Starting fresh with a new blog in a new place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess I should maybe start with what this blog is and why I’m doing it. The blog itself is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; blog run off &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com&quot;&gt;Github Pages&lt;/a&gt;. The theme is &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/iwiedenm/jekyll-theme-massively-src&quot;&gt;Massively&lt;/a&gt;, which I have modified some of the HTML and CSS for to make my own. &lt;del&gt;I’ll be probably copy pasting that whole thing to the about page for future reference&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve previously made blogs using Wordpress, both the actual &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.com&quot;&gt;blog hosting platform&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.org&quot;&gt;self hosted service&lt;/a&gt;. And every time there was just some reason I couldn’t continue. Wordpress.com was just too restrictive and needed you to pay for &lt;em&gt;everything&lt;/em&gt;, whereas the self hosted one was 100% my fault cause I hosted it from my own place… and DNS isn’t fun. I’ll just leave that there. Both solutions are great, but not for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;So here I am.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; On a new service in a new place. I’ve already run into a new set of challenges. Jekyll is statically generated off of local files, so any changes to the site need to be made from a computer that has these files. And while I can share them all through GitHub, it still severely restricts where I can make changes to my site. Also, Ruby is… picky. I am actually writing this post from my grandparents’ house in Mexico, with no internet connection. I attempt to run the Jekyll build function, but it says I’m missing a file that’s on the PC, and the self fix tool needs internet access. So I’m completely blind to what this post will even look like when done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Could not find ffi-1.9.18 in any of the sources&lt;/code&gt; This error message will haunt my dreams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So… I’ve talked about what I’m doing, and the challenges I’ve faced. But &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt;? &lt;strong&gt;Why&lt;/strong&gt; am I putting myself through this? Is it masochism? Is it some weird social experiment? Honestly… I don’t know. I just know I need an outlet. I have an overactive mind. I suffer from what my friend lovingly called &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;creative blue balls&lt;/code&gt;. In my day job, in my life, in my band, there’s not many outlets for me to let go and publish what’s going on in my head. I need a dumping ground that isn’t my notes app(shoutout to &lt;a href=&quot;https://bear.app&quot;&gt;Bear&lt;/a&gt;). I need something public, even if no one will read it, to host my ideas. I need a sort of public journal to come back to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also essentially need a portfolio. I am doing what I can to shape my life and make it so I can make my way into freelancing, and I need a way to show what I’m really about. So I guess there’s that too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stick around I guess. I can guarantee I’ll be writing more.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">I've had two blogs, and abandoned both. So... I'm launching my third blog... What am I Doing Here.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to Jekyll!</title><link href="zaza.studio/zazathebassist.github.io/blog/welcome-to-jekyll/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to Jekyll!" /><published>2018-09-11T02:39:53-07:00</published><updated>2018-09-11T02:39:53-07:00</updated><id>zaza.studio/zazathebassist.github.io/blog/welcome-to-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="zaza.studio/zazathebassist.github.io/blog/welcome-to-jekyll/">&lt;blockquote&gt; I am leaving this default page up, both because I really like Jekyll and want to emphasize that this blog was done in Jekyll and anyone can do it... and it serves as good documentation for me. &lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll find this post in your &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt;, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To add new posts, simply add a file in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory that follows the convention &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;YYYY-MM-DD-name-of-post.ext&lt;/code&gt; and includes the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Hi, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'Tom'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints 'Hi, Tom' to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/home&quot;&gt;Jekyll docs&lt;/a&gt; for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;. If you have questions, you can ask them on &lt;a href=&quot;https://talk.jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll Talk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">I am leaving this default page up, both because I really like Jekyll and want to emphasize that this blog was done in Jekyll and anyone can do it... and it serves as good documentation for me.</summary></entry></feed>
