<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xml" href="zaza.studio/zazathebassist.github.io/feed.xslt.xml"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.2.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="zaza.studio/zazathebassist.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="zaza.studio/zazathebassist.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-04-11T22:37:43-07:00</updated><id>zaza.studio/zazathebassist.github.io/</id><title type="html">Project Incomplete</title><subtitle>Emmanuel Medina's Personal Blog, Portfolio, and page to mess around</subtitle><entry><title type="html">iOS Game Reviews: Elder Scrolls Blades</title><link href="zaza.studio/zazathebassist.github.io/blog/ios-game-review-elder-scrolls-blades/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="iOS Game Reviews: Elder Scrolls Blades" /><published>2019-04-11T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-04-11T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>zaza.studio/zazathebassist.github.io/blog/ios-game-review-elder-scrolls-blades</id><content type="html" xml:base="zaza.studio/zazathebassist.github.io/blog/ios-game-review-elder-scrolls-blades/">&lt;p&gt;I want to love Elder Scrolls: Blades. I do. I really really do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[Good image of ES World]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/es-blades/es-title.png&quot; alt=&quot;Title Screen - I wish it lived up to the hype of seeing this page&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m starting this off by saying that I am a huge fan of the Elder Scrolls series. I have put more hours than I can count into Oblivion and almost as many into Skyrim. Elder Scrolls Online is in my top 5 MMOs. So I wanted, so desperately, for a mobile game to capture the feeling of Elder Scrolls. The massive world, the progression, the sense of exploration, the feeling of almost endless depth (even if that depth is almost irrelevant to the actual game).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This game. Does not. Do that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;overview&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lets start with what the game is. It is a mobile RPG for iOS and Android. You come back from being exiled as a member of the Blades to find your hometown destroyed. There are three game modes, Town, Abyss, and Arena. The gameplay is similar in all of them. It is a 3D First Person RPG, like Skyrim, ESO, and the Elder Scrolls games in the past. You move by tapping the ground to the location you’ll be walking towards. If you go into combat, it focuses in on the enemy and you tap and hold to attack, or click icons to use Magic or Ranged attacks. You can collect items in dungeons by tapping them, or talk to people, again, by tapping on them. A huge aspect of the game is rebuilding a city that was destroyed, in true ES fashion by Magic, by collecting in game currency and resources. Before we even get to the story, or the freemium aspects of Blades, or the game modes, I have to talk about the controls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;controls&quot;&gt;Controls&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/es-blades/movement.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Aaaaaand Walking&quot; title=&quot;Everyone turns exactly like that.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While this game in many points feels like it was built from the ground up to be a mobile game, it feels like it was built by people who have never played a mobile game. The game can be played both vertically and horizontally. Vertically, swiping on the screen will allow you to look around. Tapping on the ground will move your character. Horizontally this still works, but swiping on what feels like the bottom left 1/8th of the screen will allow you to walk like an analog stick, and swiping on the bottom right 1/8th will move the screen like a right analog stick. This isn’t &lt;em&gt;bad&lt;/em&gt; per se, but it leads to awkwardness.
The movement with tapping feels far worse than with the virtual analog stick. When tapping on the ground to move, the game will automatically take control of the camera, sometimes hilariously badly. Walking up stairs, the actual view you have is terrible, looking up about 45 degrees, and when you reach the top of the stairs your view stays in that position. If you click something around a corner, the character will strafe in a very unusual way around the corner. It &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; something you can get used to, but definitely annoying. It’s definitely more of a “get used to” issue, but still feels like an oversight by the game devs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, in landscape, the game plays very well. The movement is smooth when using the virtual joysticks. Your character feels like he’s actually moving. The camera moves a tad slow but it feels a lot more natural horizontally than vertically. It kind of gives this game a feeling like the vertical mode/one hand mode was added way later in development, and the devs didn’t quite know what to do with a mobile game. Movement can be a bit awkward but is something you can get used to. What I couldn’t get used to was the combat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;combat&quot;&gt;Combat&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/es-blades/combat.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Pop the bubble&quot; title=&quot;This goblin's having too much fun&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Combat is where this game fully stops feeling like an Elder Scrolls game. You tap and hold to charge an attack, and let go to release it. If you release &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; when the charging circle gets to its ready indicator, you get a critical hit. You also get buttons on the screen for using abilities and Magic. However, it is a far cry from an actual Elder Scrolls game, where you move, run, use abilities, attack, block, and (in Skyrim) using Shouts. Most fights usually end up being “can you tap correctly” and “are you stronger than the enemy” and that’s it. Any depth is lost in the lack of responsiveness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;story&quot;&gt;Story&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/es-blades/story.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Nothing to see Here&quot; title=&quot;Exploding statues are normal&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you launch the game, you get a quick instance where your character is introduced. In traditional Elder Scrolls fashion, &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; happened and you’re starting life from scratch. Unlike riding a cart to your death, or waking up in a prison, you’re heading home because you were a member of the “Blades” a kind of Secret Service in Tamriel that got disbanded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You defeat a few mercenaries and make your way to town. &lt;em&gt;Because Elder Scrolls&lt;/em&gt; and there having to be some supernatural disaster, the town is destroyed. Then the actual game starts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides this, there are quest missions that further your personal story, discovering who you were and with backstory on what happened to the Blades, as well as insight into the town and the magic beneath it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;town&quot;&gt;Town&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/es-blades/es-town.png&quot; alt=&quot;Town... needs some repair&quot; title=&quot;Fix me please&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Town is the Main game mode in ES: Blades. You will go on Quests to rescue town members, or to do tasks that those town members need done (Kill Goblins, Collect Resources, etc.), and get gold and resources that will then help you rebuild the Town. There is a lot to do in the town. You are tasked with rebuilding important buildings like the Blacksmith or Alchemist, which will unlock shops and new weapons/items. And, because this is a mobile Freemium game, the first few buildings are fairly cheap to build, and the price goes up fairly quickly from there, requiring way more time and resources to rebuild. There is also a “Jobs” board that has quests on them, including a Daily and Weekly Quest that has better rewards. These jobs will also drop you into a dungeon instance, just like the quests from town members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The actual instances are where I feel the game really falling apart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dungeons&quot;&gt;Dungeons&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have so much to say about the dungeons, but I’ll start with this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt; Doom had better level design. &lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay that’s a low blow. I’ll be nicer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;*Temple Run has never looked better* &lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dungeons are all more or less the same. They are a set of twisting hallways and rectangular rooms. The dungeons are mostly linear, you walk through the dungeon, kill the NPCs, break some breakables(usually pots), find a few chests, get to the end, rinse, repeat. And this is where I feel the game starts falling apart and you see it for what it is, not an Elder Scrolls game, but just another mobile Freemium game. There is no interesting dungeon design. There are no puzzles. There’s no feeling like you’re in a natural environment. Caves don’t feel like caves, hideouts don’t feel like hideouts. It all feels like randomly twisting passages into random rooms. Besides occasional staircases, the map is more or less flat. While you can say this is a consideration for being a mobile game, there’s plenty of unexplored space on how you can make an interesting dungeon fit for mobile games, instead of just boiling down the formula used on main ES games into its most basic elements, then creating a map that doesn’t even approach a game from 1993s in terms of being interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You get a certain amount of decent quests a day so even dungeoneering kinda has a limited lifespan. You go through the dungeon, endure clunky combat, and get rewards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;abyss&quot;&gt;Abyss&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of Dungeons, an actual interesting new feature of ES: Blades is the Abyss. The Abyss is a Rogue-lite game mode where a dungeon is randomly generated and you have to fight your way through it. I was &lt;em&gt;so excited&lt;/em&gt; for this game mode because I love rogue-like and rogue-lite games. Rogue Legacy is one of my favorite games, and I’ve put more hours than I’d like to admit into NetHack. This. Isn’t that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You end up going through a randomly snaking passage into 1-2 rooms. Clear out the NPC enemies, and then you make your way through more passageways till you reach a stairway to make your way down to the next level. And repeat. Enemies get harder as you go down, and every 5 levels it saves your progress so when you go in, you can resume from that level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I talked about how much I loved rogue likes. However, this game fully falls on its face and this game mode feels as half baked as the rest of the game. The levels of the dungeon are short. Like… painfully short. I understand that it is a mobile game but they’re short for that. {this can change, revise this}[The enemies feel squishy. There is very little challenge when it comes to the actual combat in the Abyss]. There is little to no exploration, since the actual game mode is about as linear as possible. There’s nothing to discover going down the Abyss. And it feels more like a game of attrition than anything else. How long can you last till your health is drained. That’s it. The Abyss is, in my mind, a great idea for an Elder Scrolls game. No matter how big the ES world is, there’s only so many dungeons Bethesda can design, and having an endless randomly generated dungeon is a great idea. But the lack of interesting anything, lack of complexity, and clunky feel has this feeling like the rest of the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ambiance-and-feel&quot;&gt;Ambiance and Feel&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, Elder Scrolls: Blades feels like an Elder Scrolls game without any soul. The Town feels like a generic high fantasy village. There’s not much distinct there that makes it feel like it’s anywhere in Tamriel. A lot of the icons just feel lifted from Oblivion or Skyrim. The town itself might have been made to look generic because it is to be decorated by the players, but even then it feels closer to a generic iOS game than something that belongs in an Elder Scrolls game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The skill system is expanive, and in the time I’ve played I haven’t gotten to go too far down it, but it’s definitely one of the more polished parts of the game, and feels like the one part you can really plan out progression related to the non-city aspects in the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dungeons look samey. This has always been an issue in the ES games, but at least on main releases there were puzzles or challenges, or different, non-linear designs to hold the dungeons up. These feel about as generic as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The music feels like a bad cover band’s version of Skyrim’s music. It fits the tropes of Fantasy music. It is “epic”, feels like its in a minor key to have some somber moments but still “uplifting”. It’s full of strings. But it just feels like generic music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fact that the game is instanced, while it is definitely necessary for a mobile game, pulls you out of the game itself. And when part of the selling point of every Elder Scrolls game before this &lt;em&gt;was&lt;/em&gt; immersion, I feel like this is a big step back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;looking-forward&quot;&gt;Looking Forward&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It looks like Bethesda is listening though. Between when I started writing this review and right before it went out, I got this push notificaiton.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/es-blades/notification.png&quot; alt=&quot;I thought I had notifications turned off&quot; title=&quot;DING!... We're listening&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They are actively trying to do things to make it feel less freemium. This is something I would never expect from a company like(and I hate to pick on them cause they make good games) Supercell. They’ve also added confirmation screens for spending any large amount of gems(over 11 says their patch notes) and changed percentages on chest drops. This is good news that Bethesda is listening and this game is more than the cash grab it felt like at the beginning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is also the Arena coming soon. Where ES: Blades players can fight against each other. The Arena may be a very good reason for more competitive players. I’m personally not too keen on PvP on mobile, mostly cause the chances I get for mobile games are maybe a few minutes on the toilet at work, But the option is there, and combat between players I would expect to both feel more natural and actually be more engaging than combat with NPCs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;final-thoughts&quot;&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honestly, if this game was not an Elder Scrolls game, I would have just ignored it in the app store as another freemium game trying to make a quick buck. It has all the trappings of freemium games, multiple game modes that all rely on timers; a limited amount of short, semi-interesting engaging sections(Jobs/Quests) that you need to wait real world time to reappear, a chest system that takes real world time to open, with the option of paying real world money to speed up. The gameplay is just engaging enough to keep playing, and the city building hits all the right spots for me. But even just two weeks after it’s released, I find myself reaching for other games on my phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since this is my first review, I had to figure out how I’m gonna rate games. I think an out of Five system works well, especially for iOS games since there’s such a range of games, and experience, that anything more granular feels like it’d be too specific to be useful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;

# Elder Scrolls: Blades - 3/5

 Disclaimer: ES: Blades is in Beta/Early Access and a lot is subject to change. I will add a section about Arena below the final score in an edit once it is released

### The Good
* Semi-engaging gameplay
* Interesting city building aspect
* Decent graphics
* It's an Elder Scrolls Game. On your phone
* Runs very smooth, even on an iPhone 7

### The Bad
* Clunky Movement when not using Virtual Joysticks
* Over-reliance on Freemium aspects like timers on chests and buildings, gems, and quest refresh
* Uninspired music and visuals that would fit basically any fantasy game, none really feeling Elder Scrolls like
* Weak Combat
* Difficult to play in short bursts, not enough content for longer gameplay

&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Review by Emmanuel Medina&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">I want to love Elder Scrolls: Blades. I do. I really really do.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2019: Year of Content</title><link href="zaza.studio/zazathebassist.github.io/blog/year-of-content/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2019: Year of Content" /><published>2019-01-05T23:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2019-01-05T23:00:00-08:00</updated><id>zaza.studio/zazathebassist.github.io/blog/year-of-content</id><content type="html" xml:base="zaza.studio/zazathebassist.github.io/blog/year-of-content/">&lt;p&gt;I’ve been thinking about my 2019 plan for a while. And after the absolute failure that 2018: Year of Less was, but also the kinda semi success of 2017: Year of Completion, and the success of my 2016: Year of Me, I was excited to talk about my new theme. Also New Years Resolutions are dumb.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of the reason I started this blog is to chronicle my yearly themes. I’ll probably repost my old themes &lt;del&gt;but no promises&lt;/del&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been thinking about a more realistic yearly theme for a while. And thinking about what I want to do in my life going forward. And I realized no matter what, I want to be producing something. I want to be making some kind of content. Be it podcasts, videos, watercolors, making pens, or just keeping this blog up. I’m happiest when I’m making something. It’s just a really nice feeling making something appear out of nothing. And so, for 2019, I’m focusing on content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2018 I’ve done a few things sporadically. I made a Youtube review video(might have been late 2017 but I think it was this year), started podcasts/podcast editing, and got a bit back into painting. But it was so disjointed, and I kept just… doing other things when I had small amounts of time. But making sure I keep myself accountable to this is a big part of the year’s Theme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For people who may not know, yearly themes is a topic that kind of came to be, or was at least first brought to my attention, by the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.relay.fm/cortex/79&quot;&gt;Cortex&lt;/a&gt; podcast. Myke and Grey have been doing yearly themes for a few years. And the whole idea is that you don’t have a set goal, because goals fail. You set a theme to help guide decisions. It just helps guide your ideas and thought process, and keeps the theme an active part of your mind that you can focus on, instead of wishful thinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I need that because it is really easy for me to lose focus. The last few months of my life I’ve mostly lost direction and kinda been meandering through work and responsibilities and I needed better focus on my life going forward.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">I’ve been thinking about my 2019 plan for a while. And after the absolute failure that 2018: Year of Less was, but also the kinda semi success of 2017: Year of Completion, and the success of my 2016: Year of Me, I was excited to talk about my new theme. Also New Years Resolutions are dumb.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Accidental Disconnect from the Internet</title><link href="zaza.studio/zazathebassist.github.io/blog/accidental-disconnect/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Accidental Disconnect from the Internet" /><published>2018-12-28T23:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2018-12-28T23:00:00-08:00</updated><id>zaza.studio/zazathebassist.github.io/blog/accidental-disconnect</id><content type="html" xml:base="zaza.studio/zazathebassist.github.io/blog/accidental-disconnect/">&lt;p&gt;It’s been an odd month or two for me. For the first time in as long as I can remember, I’ve been mostly disconnected from the internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This wasn’t really any kind of planned event. I had recently become more active on the Do By Friday discord, was fairly active with my bands social media, rediscovered Twitter a third time, and was actually enjoying Instagram. Then, shortly before I took my trip to Mexico, my use basically plummited. Mexico certainly helped, I ran out of data shortly after my plane arrived and I had basically nothing but simple texting for a week. But even after that, my usage of almost all social media went down to near zero.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been thinking about my internet usage for a while. It definitely was something on my mind since I took a trip to Yosemite in April because, turns out, there’s almost no cell signals, and I felt &lt;em&gt;fine&lt;/em&gt;. I didn’t feel like I was missing out in anything, or like I would fall apart if something happened online and I didn’t come across it. But the moment I got back into society, I went back on my phone. I got a new laptop, went to WWDC, got involved in multiple online communities, hell met my SO online. But I had this feeling that I needed to get away from it all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was not made easier by CGP Grey releasing a lot of content relating to his sabbatical from the internet. It framed the internet as a bad thing that is affecting his focus, and it kind of made me uncomfortable how it brought into focus my relationship with the internet. But I was in denial. Grey is dumb, it’s not the internet’s fault, it’s how his brain works, or it’s actually x or y, or he remembers the past wrong and was always like this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt; Then, I kinda just disconnected from the internet... and he was right. And I felt like a slightly better person while doing it. &lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It gave me a good chance to reflect on what the Internet was really doing to me. I don’t believe that it is affecting my attention like other do, that comes from elsewhere. But it definitely was affecting my sanity, because right before my disconnect, were the 2018 Midterm Elections. Elections whose news stories I tracked, whose stats I watched, whose follow up I kept such a close eye on to see which races flipped where at what points due to mail in ballots or issues with voting or otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I went from that, to a period where I had almost no political news. Almost no news whatsoever actually. I felt &lt;em&gt;free&lt;/em&gt;. But the terrible part is that I felt free &lt;em&gt;after&lt;/em&gt; I realized and started reconnecting. &lt;em&gt;After&lt;/em&gt; I started refollowing tech sites, political sites, started getting back on Reddit and Twitter, I realized how much those sites impacted me. How sad and stressed they truly made me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I’m left with a dilemma. What am I to do. What could I possibly do to take care of myself. The solution I think I landed on is, sadly, “more technology.” I have picked up a calendar and task manager app(I’ll write about those later) to help me focus on what I &lt;em&gt;have&lt;/em&gt; to do instead of what I &lt;em&gt;want to&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;shouldn’t&lt;/em&gt; do online. I’ve started just browsing news sites on my PC but saving interesting articles to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instapaper.com/&quot;&gt;Instapaper&lt;/a&gt; so I could read the actual articles in a well designed, clutter free location so I can only focus on one thing. I am thinking about something like an Apple Watch so I can segment notifications into things I need to see on the Watch and things I can ignore on the phone. I’ve turned off basically every notification on my phone minus calls, texts, and Omnifocus(this included getting rid of email notifications, that 30,000+ red bubble). I’m considering an iPad for purely writing and reading web articles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a lot to think about. I have some travel in Mid-January that will force another short disconnect from the internet. So I’m going to see how much that affects me. But I’m sure that I’ll be back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mean… I just started a blog that I’m actually keeping up kinda sorta just a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn’t the end of my experiment. But I will definitely be something I think about a LOT in the coming year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wf2VxeIm1no&quot;&gt;CGP Grey’s Disconnect YouTube Video&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.relay.fm/cortex/74&quot;&gt;Disconnect Discussion on Cortex&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">It’s been an odd month or two for me. For the first time in as long as I can remember, I’ve been mostly disconnected from the internet.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Coming Back to Magic</title><link href="zaza.studio/zazathebassist.github.io/blog/coming-back-to-magic/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Coming Back to Magic" /><published>2018-12-04T23:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2018-12-04T23:00:00-08:00</updated><id>zaza.studio/zazathebassist.github.io/blog/coming-back-to-magic</id><content type="html" xml:base="zaza.studio/zazathebassist.github.io/blog/coming-back-to-magic/">&lt;p&gt;I left Magic about two years ago. It was a slow fade, and once I was done I thought I was out. I thought I quit this Cardboard Crack&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OH NO&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You &lt;em&gt;don’t&lt;/em&gt; just leave Magic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I’m &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;so glad&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; I’m back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Backstory. I stopped playing Magic about two years ago mostly due to money and time. I couldn’t justify the entry fee, or the time commitment every Friday. So I stopped going. I still kept up with some news, but without playing, that slowed down too. I couldn’t play Magic Online, because that is a steaming pile of garbage(more on that later) and Magic stopped being a part of my life. And when I finally wanted to get back into it, my LGS shut down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was deep into Magic. Like… deep in the competitive circle. My LGS was one of the most competitive stores in all SoCal. And with it shutting down, I felt like even if I wanted to start again, I couldn’t. Most other LGSs in my area(which were still 30 minute drive from me) were really casual, and none of the people I had become friends with went to them. And the nearest “competitive” store, where most of the players moved to, was an hours drive away. I did not have a chance to get back into Magic even if I wanted to. A local GP passed and I didn’t go. I would go to every major event in SoCal beforehand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then came Magic Arena.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Image3_Izzet.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MTGA_Gameplay&quot; title=&quot;Magic Arena is Beautiful&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Magic Arena is a brand new client designed by Wizards of the Coast to play Magic online. Magic Arena is also currently in Open Beta, but I’ve been playing since the closed beta. And it has revived in me a love of Magic I thought I lost a while ago. The other online offerings were bad. So I touched no online way to play Magic until Arena. And Arena is something else. I was skeptical at first, because the last attempt was really bad(people are still crying about MTGO v4). But boy was I wrong. The experience is smooth, the gameplay exceptional, it has a very Apple-like sense of &lt;em&gt;Discoverability&lt;/em&gt; where features you don’t need will be barely hidden, but when you finally need it they’ll be out in the open. It is &lt;em&gt;full Magic&lt;/em&gt; with all the insane rule complexities of Magic, but with a design and interface that is stellar for both new players and veterans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But all this is just praising the client itself, what I really am here to do is talk about how it helped me rediscover a love I thought I lost. I had tried, in the time I was away from Magic, to fill that void. I played Hearthstone religiously for a few months. But it lacked a depth that Magic had. I tried MTGO, but the economy is a direct mirror of paper MTG for absolutely no reason and the actual program looks like it’s written for Windows 95, and has stability to match. But here was a version of Magic that captured everything that made paper Magic so wonderful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Magic is a game I will praise until the end of time. It is so well designed, and the R&amp;amp;D Team at Wizards really does their best to make sure it is still relevant. In the 25 years it has been around, the power creep has been so well managed that eternal decks will still play cards printed 20+ years ago, along with cards made today. And you can feel it. Magic is a game you can teach any kid old enough to logic and you can have a casual game with, but is also deep enough to evoke 20+ years of game theory on, and still have emerging thoughts even today. No other game, at least that I’ve found, has that. It is a game that massive communities have built around, a game that continues to gain fans. And Arena is the first time a program has captured this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is still early on. It is a Beta after all. Simple things like friends lists are still being worked on, and actual tournaments seem a ways away. &lt;del&gt;Plus no Mac client yet grumble grumble&lt;/del&gt;. But I just wanted to sing praises to the game that got me back into Magic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;Image Courtesy of Wizards of the Coast&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">I left Magic about two years ago. It was a slow fade, and once I was done I thought I was out. I thought I quit this Cardboard Crack</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Back to Living in Fear</title><link href="zaza.studio/zazathebassist.github.io/blog/back-in-fear/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Back to Living in Fear" /><published>2018-11-22T23:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2018-11-22T23:00:00-08:00</updated><id>zaza.studio/zazathebassist.github.io/blog/back-in-fear</id><content type="html" xml:base="zaza.studio/zazathebassist.github.io/blog/back-in-fear/">&lt;p&gt;When I was a kid, I had one big fear. Most kids were scared of heights, or the dark, or the monster under the bed. I was scared of being pulled over. I was scared that the cops were going to take away my mom and dad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a child of immigrants. I wont go into it too much, but I’ll just say both my parents are citizens now. They weren’t then. I would get bouts of anxiety if my dad took too long to get home. Did they finally pull him over? Did he run into an immigration checkpoint(they were common in California). Is tonight the night I lose my dad? This was a time before cell phones were common, so I was doubly paranoid. But time passes. Those checkpoints became less common, and my parents went through the process to naturalize.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why am I writing about this now. Why am I talking about a childhood fear? Because today, on Thanksgiving day when I’m writing this, that fear came back. That fear that started lingering in the back of my mind since November 2016 came back full force. But this time, it’s me, and I’m scared if I’ll ever make it home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, writing this, on Thanksgiving Day 2018, Donald Trump, in a fit of imbecilic rage, announced that he is authorizing the use of force on the Mexican border, and is considering outright closing it. Also, today on Thanksgiving Day, I am in Mexico, on the other side of the Mexican border, with plane tickets to go back in a few days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt; &quot;Earlier on Thursday, U.S. President Donald Trump said he had authorized the use of lethal force on the border and warned that the United States could close the whole frontier.&quot; - &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/article/us-usa-immigration-caravan/tensions-rise-at-u-s-mexico-border-as-migrants-holiday-travelers-wait-to-cross-idUSKCN1NS01A&quot;&gt;Reuters&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is everything I feared. It is the reality of so many people, that our President, someone elected who &lt;em&gt;lost the popular vote&lt;/em&gt; could make one decision and ruin so many lives. But worse, it pulls me back to that kid, home from school, worried that his dad won’t come home tonight. Or who sees flashing police lights up ahead and wonders if it will be my last day in the US.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t know why I’m writing this. I don’t have a point. Trump is in office for two more years. If they truly close the border there’s other legal ways for American Citizens to enter the country. I would be thrown into a financial hole if that happens, but life would go on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I needed this off my chest. I needed to vent. To scream. To &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;FUCKING SCREAM&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. Because today, I saw my life disappear. In one rash string of tweets, on the day where Americans are supposed to be celebrating the hospitality the natives showed what was ostensively a group of immigrants, one statement threw me into a panic attack. One statement made me cry. And I’m filled with pure hopelessness, because I know it won’t be the last time.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">When I was a kid, I had one big fear. Most kids were scared of heights, or the dark, or the monster under the bed. I was scared of being pulled over. I was scared that the cops were going to take away my mom and dad.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Test Blog Part 3!</title><link href="zaza.studio/zazathebassist.github.io/blog/test-blog-part-3/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Test Blog Part 3!" /><published>2018-11-21T01:39:53-08:00</published><updated>2018-11-21T01:39:53-08:00</updated><id>zaza.studio/zazathebassist.github.io/blog/test-blog-part-3</id><content type="html" xml:base="zaza.studio/zazathebassist.github.io/blog/test-blog-part-3/">&lt;blockquote&gt; I've had two blogs, and abandoned both. So... I'm launching my third blog... What am I Doing Here. &lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Blog-text.png&quot; alt=&quot;Side note, Atom is a fantastic text editor&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ask myself that all too much. This is the 3rd blog I try(4th if you count tumblr… I don’t) in earnest to start. And it’s been up in some capacity since September, without updates, so even before I get it in a decent state I already feel like I failed(I talk more about my view on failure Here). But here I am. Starting fresh with a new blog in a new place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess I should maybe start with what this blog is and why I’m doing it. The blog itself is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; blog run off &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com&quot;&gt;Github Pages&lt;/a&gt;. The theme is &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/iwiedenm/jekyll-theme-massively-src&quot;&gt;Massively&lt;/a&gt;, which I have modified some of the HTML and CSS for to make my own. &lt;del&gt;I’ll be probably copy pasting that whole thing to the about page for future reference&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve previously made blogs using Wordpress, both the actual &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.com&quot;&gt;blog hosting platform&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://wordpress.org&quot;&gt;self hosted service&lt;/a&gt;. And every time there was just some reason I couldn’t continue. Wordpress.com was just too restrictive and needed you to pay for &lt;em&gt;everything&lt;/em&gt;, whereas the self hosted one was 100% my fault cause I hosted it from my own place… and DNS isn’t fun. I’ll just leave that there. Both solutions are great, but not for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;So here I am.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; On a new service in a new place. I’ve already run into a new set of challenges. Jekyll is statically generated off of local files, so any changes to the site need to be made from a computer that has these files. And while I can share them all through GitHub, it still severely restricts where I can make changes to my site. Also, Ruby is… picky. I am actually writing this post from my grandparents’ house in Mexico, with no internet connection. I attempt to run the Jekyll build function, but it says I’m missing a file that’s on the PC, and the self fix tool needs internet access. So I’m completely blind to what this post will even look like when done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Could not find ffi-1.9.18 in any of the sources&lt;/code&gt; This error message will haunt my dreams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So… I’ve talked about what I’m doing, and the challenges I’ve faced. But &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt;? &lt;strong&gt;Why&lt;/strong&gt; am I putting myself through this? Is it masochism? Is it some weird social experiment? Honestly… I don’t know. I just know I need an outlet. I have an overactive mind. I suffer from what my friend lovingly called &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;creative blue balls&lt;/code&gt;. In my day job, in my life, in my band, there’s not many outlets for me to let go and publish what’s going on in my head. I need a dumping ground that isn’t my notes app(shoutout to &lt;a href=&quot;https://bear.app&quot;&gt;Bear&lt;/a&gt;). I need something public, even if no one will read it, to host my ideas. I need a sort of public journal to come back to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also essentially need a portfolio. I am doing what I can to shape my life and make it so I can make my way into freelancing, and I need a way to show what I’m really about. So I guess there’s that too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stick around I guess. I can guarantee I’ll be writing more.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">I've had two blogs, and abandoned both. So... I'm launching my third blog... What am I Doing Here.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to Jekyll!</title><link href="zaza.studio/zazathebassist.github.io/blog/welcome-to-jekyll/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to Jekyll!" /><published>2018-09-11T02:39:53-07:00</published><updated>2018-09-11T02:39:53-07:00</updated><id>zaza.studio/zazathebassist.github.io/blog/welcome-to-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="zaza.studio/zazathebassist.github.io/blog/welcome-to-jekyll/">&lt;blockquote&gt; I am leaving this default page up, both because I really like Jekyll and want to emphasize that this blog was done in Jekyll and anyone can do it... and it serves as good documentation for me. &lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’ll find this post in your &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt;, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To add new posts, simply add a file in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory that follows the convention &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;YYYY-MM-DD-name-of-post.ext&lt;/code&gt; and includes the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Hi, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'Tom'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints 'Hi, Tom' to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/home&quot;&gt;Jekyll docs&lt;/a&gt; for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;. If you have questions, you can ask them on &lt;a href=&quot;https://talk.jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll Talk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">I am leaving this default page up, both because I really like Jekyll and want to emphasize that this blog was done in Jekyll and anyone can do it... and it serves as good documentation for me.</summary></entry></feed>
