<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>yearly theme on critical point</title>
    <link>https://emmaceleste.gay/categories/yearly-theme/</link>
    <description>Recent content in yearly theme on critical point</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://emmaceleste.gay/categories/yearly-theme/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Yearly Theme 2022: Year of Creation</title>
      <link>https://emmaceleste.gay/posts/yearly-theme-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://emmaceleste.gay/posts/yearly-theme-2022/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s that time of year again. Yearly Theme time. And I want to coast off the success of last year&amp;rsquo;s theme. Last year I set myself on the path of the Year of Discovery. And through that, I explored more of California and of myself then I have in a long time. I am content that I marked a good path that will allow me to keep moving forward and explore myself and the world around me more.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s that time of year again. Yearly Theme time. And I want to coast off the success of last year&amp;rsquo;s theme. Last year I set myself on the path of the Year of Discovery. And through that, I explored more of California and of myself then I have in a long time. I am content that I marked a good path that will allow me to keep moving forward and explore myself and the world around me more. But I want to do more than just see new things. I want to create. I have this need in me not just to observe the beauty of this world, but to contribute to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is why this year I am setting off on the Year of Creation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creativity has been something I have struggled with regularly throughout my life. I have regularly wanted to or tried to pursue creative venues, but either because of some bad executive dysfunction, overly busy schedules, or imposter syndrome I have ended up not following through. My most creative solo venture, my TikTok page, lasted essentially 4 months before I needed to take a break. I&amp;rsquo;m not happy about that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I feel like I have entered a new part of my life. One where I am able to dedicate the time and energy to create in the ways I want to, and I want a theme that will help me pursue this better. But the big thing here is what I mean by &amp;ldquo;creativity&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And honestly, I&amp;rsquo;m keeping it pretty open and vague for a reason. I have a lot of creative outlets and would rather just set myself the goal of creating &lt;em&gt;something beautiful&lt;/em&gt; instead of trying to lock it down to something more specific like &amp;ldquo;write a song a month&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;upload a TikTok a week&amp;rdquo;. This is more about building a habit of making things than it is the actual output.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And to add to that, a big part of this is going to be not caring about the quality of my finished product. I am not trying to make an album that will chart or another TikTok that breaks 100k views. I&amp;rsquo;m just trying to be me, and create things that I like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The creative venues I have available to me are&amp;hellip; too many. But I would like to spend more time creating music and video content. Above all, I always come back to music and video as the two creative venues that fill me with the most joy and offset that difficulty I have in creating stuff. I don&amp;rsquo;t like setting myself goals, but I want to have music published. I have run a semi-successful video channel already, music is the one venue I have not truly been able to just make my own. It has always been tied to other people. And with my band in a &lt;em&gt;difficult spot&lt;/em&gt;, this year more than ever will be a good year for this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, here I go. This article is part of the Year of Creation. I got two blog posts out in a week. I don&amp;rsquo;t expect to keep this pace, but I wanna keep this energy through the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The concept of yearly themes comes from the podcast &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.relay.fm/cortex/79&#34;&gt;Cortex&lt;/a&gt; with CGP Grey and Myke Hurley. They have genuinely helped me think of my life in a way better way. You can also check them out a video that Grey made about yearly themes here &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NVGuFdX5guE&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NVGuFdX5guE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yearly Theme Wrap-up 2021: Year of Discovery</title>
      <link>https://emmaceleste.gay/posts/yearly-theme-2021-retrospective/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://emmaceleste.gay/posts/yearly-theme-2021-retrospective/</guid>
      <description>I did not expect 2021 to be a whole second year of Covid. When I chose my yearly theme, the Vaccine had been completed and it looked like full vaccinations would happen by the end of Spring. How could I have foreseen Covid being so political that almost a year after after the vaccine started being given, we would be at 61% of the country vaccinated, and have experienced two variants and three whole waves requiring the wold to continue shutting down.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;I did not expect 2021 to be a whole second year of Covid. When I chose my yearly theme, the Vaccine had been completed and it looked like full vaccinations would happen by the end of Spring. How could I have foreseen Covid being so political that almost a year after after the vaccine started being given, we would be at 61% of the country vaccinated, and have experienced two variants and three whole waves requiring the wold to continue shutting down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But this isn&amp;rsquo;t a retrospective on a year of Covid, it&amp;rsquo;s a retrospective on my year. When I started this year, I told myself I would make it my Year of Discovery. I spent too much of 2020 stagnating. I knew there was a chance for Covid to not disappear and my Year of Discovery was &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; predicated on Covid disappearing. I am generally happy with how I did and I&amp;rsquo;m glad at the clarity that Year of Discovery provided me. I even reconnected with some friends in a way that has done nothing but made my life better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;music&#34;&gt;Music&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Music is probably the place I progressed the least. I did play guitar and bass more than I did in 2020, but that wasn&amp;rsquo;t by much. However, I will take any progress I can. I started a pedal collection and started playing around with creating soundscapes and I discovered a new love for the creation of music. I have set myself up to create more music as time goes on and I have slowly started repairing my relationship with music. My band situation is uh &lt;em&gt;complicated&lt;/em&gt; but I have faith things will work out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;exploration&#34;&gt;Exploration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have taken 2021 to explore so much of what I wanted. I didn&amp;rsquo;t do nearly as much as I wanted to, but that&amp;rsquo;s life isn&amp;rsquo;t it. I picked up an annual pass for both the Natural History Museum and Universal Studios. I know they&amp;rsquo;re not remotely similar but both show me expanding. I did get my Amateur Radio License. I&amp;rsquo;ve done other small things over the year (gotten an Xbox and played more games, went out to different places, went to concerts again) but all of them kinda show the same thing. Me exploring and growing. The wildest discovery is that I&amp;rsquo;m slowly becoming a car girl. Pls send help lol. No but seriously I got super into F1, and then Forza, and now I wanna get a beater car and do Rallycross. Send help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;relationships&#34;&gt;Relationships&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is probably the most surprising thing to come from this year. I started this year with a messy breakup and a lot of introspection needed onto what I wanted and needed in a relationship. I fully expected 2021 to be a year I spent single and used that to grow. I guess mid year me had other plans because I am now in a relationship with a wonderful person. But more than that, this person has taught me so much of what a good relationship should look like. How communication should work. How to approach difficult situations. What I deserve in a relationship and what I should give. And I think the most important thing is I&amp;rsquo;ve discovered how to keep being my own person and have my own time separate from the relationship. And that is something I had struggled tremendously on. And that is something I am incredibly grateful for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;gender&#34;&gt;Gender&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay. This is a hard section to write. Not necessarily because I am still confused (tho I still am). More because I will be putting something out to the internet. This year I approached something that I had had in my periphery for a while but, I don&amp;rsquo;t know if I was just too scared or not ready for the answer. But after this year, there&amp;rsquo;s no way to deny it. I am Trans. What exactly that means I am not sure. I currently feel comfortable calling myself non-binary but I am still going through a lot of emotions. I just know that I am not cis. It helps clear up so much of why I have felt how I have for the last 26 years of my life. I think the hardest part of this year is not that I discovered that I&amp;rsquo;m trans. It&amp;rsquo;s that this is just the start of a journey that will take years. A journey that will never end. But I am looking forward to it, because it is a journey that will lead to a peace of mind that I have so desperately been looking for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;wrap-up&#34;&gt;Wrap-Up&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So where does this leave me. Oddly, both with a sense of accomplishment, but also a feeling that my journey has just started. Which, at 27 years old, is a feeling I&amp;rsquo;m starting to get tired of. I&amp;rsquo;ve discovered things about myself, and also discovered new paths for me to go down. Some of them will be dead ends, but some will lead me to becoming the best version of me that I can be. And overall, I&amp;rsquo;m happy at that. I genuinely believe this to be my most successful theme. And I hope I can keep this energy and momentum into 2022. Because I need it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The concept of yearly themes comes from the podcast &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.relay.fm/cortex/79&#34;&gt;Cortex&lt;/a&gt; with CGP Grey and Myke Hurley. They have genuinely helped me think of my life in a way better way. You can also check them out a video that Grey made about yearly themes here &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NVGuFdX5guE&#34;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NVGuFdX5guE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yearly Theme 2021: Year of Discovery</title>
      <link>https://emmaceleste.gay/posts/yearly-theme-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://emmaceleste.gay/posts/yearly-theme-2021/</guid>
      <description>So, 2020 sucked. I have been doing yearly themes since I believe 2015 and 2020 is the only year where I completely lost track of my theme. I don&amp;rsquo;t think I need to go into why covid but it&amp;rsquo;s time to get back on the train.
So for 2021, I am doing a 180 from the life I led in 2020. Last year might as well have been &amp;ldquo;the Year of Lockdown&amp;rdquo;.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;So, 2020 sucked. I have been doing yearly themes since I believe 2015 and 2020 is the only year where I completely lost track of my theme. I don&amp;rsquo;t think I need to go into why &lt;del&gt;covid&lt;/del&gt; but it&amp;rsquo;s time to get back on the train.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So for 2021, I am doing a 180 from the life I led in 2020. Last year might as well have been &amp;ldquo;the Year of Lockdown&amp;rdquo;. So to get back out there and open my horizons, I am making 2021 my &amp;ldquo;Year of Discovery&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do I mean by Discovery. There&amp;rsquo;s so much to this world that you can&amp;rsquo;t experience inside the same 4 walls. And there&amp;rsquo;s so much you can do inside those 4 walls that isn&amp;rsquo;t just binging Netflix and doomscrolling Twitter. So I am going to focus on expanding my horizons and taking advantage of what the world has to offer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the start of the year, this is gonna be a re-focus on my hobbies. I&amp;rsquo;ve set up my guitar and bass rig for the first time since Covid shut my band down. I&amp;rsquo;m exploring new ways to play either instrument that I hadn&amp;rsquo;t done before. On guitar, I&amp;rsquo;m learning how to play math rock style tapping guitar. And on bass, my band is going down to A so I&amp;rsquo;m learning how to play in A standard. Both are providing me with a new challenge and allowing me to explore a new way of playing music that I never have before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m also getting my amateur radio license. Learning Ham radio is something I have been wanting to do since High School and I realized if I keep pushing it off I&amp;rsquo;ll never get it done. So I picked up a Baofeng radio and have a test scheduled soon to get my Ham license.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides that, I&amp;rsquo;m just not letting the pandemic keep me locked up anymore. I&amp;rsquo;ve started going out hiking. I&amp;rsquo;m planning on meeting up with my band soon to actually play music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, I miss life. And my yearly theme is just a way for me to start living again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The concept of yearly themes comes from the podcast &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.relay.fm/cortex/79&#34;&gt;Cortex&lt;/a&gt; with CGP Grey and Myke Hurley. You can also check them out a video that Grey made about yearly themes &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NVGuFdX5guE&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2019: Year of Content</title>
      <link>https://emmaceleste.gay/posts/2019-yearly-theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://emmaceleste.gay/posts/2019-yearly-theme/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about my 2019 plan for a while. And after the absolute failure that 2018: Year of Less was, but also the kinda semi success of 2017: Year of Completion, and the success of my 2016: Year of Me, I was excited to talk about my new theme. Also New Years Resolutions are dumb.
Part of the reason I started this blog is to chronicle my yearly themes. I&amp;rsquo;ll probably repost my old themes but no promises.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about my 2019 plan for a while. And after the absolute failure that 2018: Year of Less was, but also the kinda semi success of 2017: Year of Completion, and the success of my 2016: Year of Me, I was excited to talk about my new theme. Also New Years Resolutions are dumb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part of the reason I started this blog is to chronicle my yearly themes. I&amp;rsquo;ll probably repost my old themes &lt;del&gt;but no promises&lt;/del&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about a more realistic yearly theme for a while. And thinking about what I want to do in my life going forward. And I realized no matter what, I want to be producing something. I want to be making some kind of content. Be it podcasts, videos, watercolors, making pens, or just keeping this blog up. I&amp;rsquo;m happiest when I&amp;rsquo;m making something. It&amp;rsquo;s just a really nice feeling making something appear out of nothing. And so, for 2019, I&amp;rsquo;m focusing on content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2018 I&amp;rsquo;ve done a few things sporadically. I made a Youtube review video(might have been late 2017 but I think it was this year), started podcasts/podcast editing, and got a bit back into painting. But it was so disjointed, and I kept just&amp;hellip; doing other things when I had small amounts of time. But making sure I keep myself accountable to this is a big part of the year&amp;rsquo;s Theme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For people who may not know, yearly themes is a topic that kind of came to be, or was at least first brought to my attention, by the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.relay.fm/cortex/79&#34;&gt;Cortex&lt;/a&gt; podcast. Myke and Grey have been doing yearly themes for a few years. And the whole idea is that you don&amp;rsquo;t have a set goal, because goals fail. You set a theme to help guide decisions. It just helps guide your ideas and thought process, and keeps the theme an active part of your mind that you can focus on, instead of wishful thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I need that because it is really easy for me to lose focus. The last few months of my life I&amp;rsquo;ve mostly lost direction and kinda been meandering through work and responsibilities and I needed better focus on my life going forward.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
