<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Critical Point</title>
    <link>https://zaza.studio/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Critical Point</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://zaza.studio/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My Favorite Songs and the Impact Music has had on My Life</title>
      <link>https://zaza.studio/p/top-songs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zaza.studio/p/top-songs/</guid>
      <description>This was first written in May 2021 but due to a mental block I didn&#39;t get it uploaded until September 2021  Music has been a massive part of my life for about as long as I remember. Just now, a friend was asking her friends about their favorite songs. That sent me down a spiral about what my favorite music is. Before, I held the position that it was impossible for me to hold a &amp;ldquo;favorite song&amp;rdquo; but now, that&amp;rsquo;s changed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yearly Theme 2021: Year of Discovery</title>
      <link>https://zaza.studio/p/yearly-theme-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zaza.studio/p/yearly-theme-2021/</guid>
      <description>So, 2020 sucked. I have been doing yearly themes since I believe 2015 and 2020 is the only year where I completely lost track of my theme. I don&amp;rsquo;t think I need to go into why covid but it&amp;rsquo;s time to get back on the train.
So for 2021, I am doing a 180 from the life I led in 2020. Last year might as well have been &amp;ldquo;the Year of Lockdown&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Darkroom Diary: Using a $35 Lens on a 10 Year Old Camera</title>
      <link>https://zaza.studio/p/darkroom-diary-35-dollar-lens/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zaza.studio/p/darkroom-diary-35-dollar-lens/</guid>
      <description>Photography is an expensive hobby. It&amp;rsquo;s one I love but definitely will suck as much money as you put into it. So when I see a lens that costs $35 on Amazon, I know I need to get it immediately.
 Fotasy Lens  Taken with iPhone 11
Fotasy 35mm f/1.6 Micro 4/3 Lens The lens I picked up is the Fotasy 35mm f/1.6 lens. It&amp;rsquo;s Micro 4/3 lens so it&amp;rsquo;s a 70mm equivalent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Darkroom Diary: iPhone Photography, and Finding Photography Again</title>
      <link>https://zaza.studio/p/iphone-photography/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zaza.studio/p/iphone-photography/</guid>
      <description>I was very into photography a few years ago. Decent DSLR, lenses, accessories, the whole deal. But for various reasons my love of photography left me. The camera was too heavy to bring, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t good enough, and I had some personal reasons. So I kinda stopped photography. The DSLR was sold off. My film camera is in a box somewhere. It all just&amp;hellip; stopped.
That changed when I got my iPhone 11.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top Ten Games of the Decade (2010-2019)</title>
      <link>https://zaza.studio/p/top-10-games-of-2010-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zaza.studio/p/top-10-games-of-2010-2019/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s the end of the 2010s and I really want to reflect on my life. But I feel like I&amp;rsquo;m in a flux part of my life and with so much happening around me, I thought it&amp;rsquo;d be easier to just do games of the decade.
A bit about me, I am a gamer but a hobbyist one at best. This is my personal list for games that impacted me the most.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oko: A Returning Player&#39;s Perspective</title>
      <link>https://zaza.studio/p/state-of-magic-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zaza.studio/p/state-of-magic-2019/</guid>
      <description>Now, I started writing this before Oko was banned but even after the Ban, I feel like I have something to say.
So I was a very into Magic a few years ago. I came into the game at the end of the Return to Ravnica block, my first event and one of the first times playing was an event called a &amp;ldquo;Magic Celebration&amp;rdquo; in 2013 where they handed out free decks and packs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iOS Game Reviews: Elder Scrolls Blades</title>
      <link>https://zaza.studio/p/ios-review-es-blades/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zaza.studio/p/ios-review-es-blades/</guid>
      <description>I want to love Elder Scrolls: Blades. I do. I really really do.
--  Title Screen - I wish it lived up to the hype of seeing this page 
I&amp;rsquo;m starting this off by saying that I am a huge fan of the Elder Scrolls series. I have put more hours than I can count into Oblivion and almost as many into Skyrim. Elder Scrolls Online is in my top 5 MMOs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2019: Year of Content</title>
      <link>https://zaza.studio/p/2019-yearly-theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zaza.studio/p/2019-yearly-theme/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about my 2019 plan for a while. And after the absolute failure that 2018: Year of Less was, but also the kinda semi success of 2017: Year of Completion, and the success of my 2016: Year of Me, I was excited to talk about my new theme. Also New Years Resolutions are dumb.
Part of the reason I started this blog is to chronicle my yearly themes. I&amp;rsquo;ll probably repost my old themes but no promises.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accidental Disconnect from the Internet</title>
      <link>https://zaza.studio/p/disconnect/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zaza.studio/p/disconnect/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been an odd month or two for me. For the first time in as long as I can remember, I&amp;rsquo;ve been mostly disconnected from the internet.
This wasn&amp;rsquo;t really any kind of planned event. I had recently become more active on the Do By Friday discord, was fairly active with my bands social media, rediscovered Twitter a third time, and was actually enjoying Instagram. Then, shortly before I took my trip to Mexico, my use basically plummited.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coming Back to Magic</title>
      <link>https://zaza.studio/p/state-of-magic-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zaza.studio/p/state-of-magic-2018/</guid>
      <description>I left Magic about two years ago. It was a slow fade, and once I was done I thought I was out. I thought I quit this Cardboard Crack
OH NO
You don&amp;rsquo;t just leave Magic.
And I&amp;rsquo;m so glad I&amp;rsquo;m back.
Backstory. I stopped playing Magic about two years ago mostly due to money and time. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t justify the entry fee, or the time commitment every Friday. So I stopped going.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back to Living in Fear</title>
      <link>https://zaza.studio/p/fear/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zaza.studio/p/fear/</guid>
      <description>When I was a kid, I had one big fear. Most kids were scared of heights, or the dark, or the monster under the bed. I was scared of being pulled over. I was scared that the cops were going to take away my mom and dad.
I&amp;rsquo;m a child of immigrants. I wont go into it too much, but I&amp;rsquo;ll just say both my parents are citizens now. They weren&amp;rsquo;t then.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test Blog Part 3!</title>
      <link>https://zaza.studio/p/test-blog-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zaza.studio/p/test-blog-part-3/</guid>
      <description>This is my 4th blog attempt. I am keeping this piece unedited to show my thought process back in 2018. Note I am no longer on Jekyll or using the Minimal Mistakes theme  I ask myself that all too much. This is the 3rd blog I try(4th if you count tumblr&amp;hellip; I don&amp;rsquo;t) in earnest to start. And it&amp;rsquo;s been up in some capacity since September, without updates, so even before I get it in a decent state I already feel like I failed(I talk more about my view on failure Here).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
