<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Archives on critical point</title>
    <link>https://zaza.studio/archive/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Archives on critical point</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://zaza.studio/archive/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Top Ten Games of the Decade (2010-2019)</title>
      <link>https://zaza.studio/archive/top-10-games-of-2010-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zaza.studio/archive/top-10-games-of-2010-2019/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s the end of the 2010s and I really want to reflect on my life. But I feel like I&amp;rsquo;m in a flux part of my life and with so much happening around me, I thought it&amp;rsquo;d be easier to just do games of the decade.
A bit about me, I am a gamer but a hobbyist one at best. This is my personal list for games that impacted me the most.</description>
      <content>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s the end of the 2010s and I really want to reflect on my life. But I feel like I&amp;rsquo;m in a flux part of my life and with so much happening around me, I thought it&amp;rsquo;d be easier to just do games of the decade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A bit about me, I am a gamer but a hobbyist one at best. This is my personal list for games that impacted me the most. It is not commentary of the &amp;ldquo;best&amp;rdquo; games, there are games I played that were objectively great that didn&amp;rsquo;t make my list because they didn&amp;rsquo;t have as much of an impact on me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;honorable-mentions&#34;&gt;Honorable Mentions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;MarioOdyssey.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Mario Odyssey&#34; title=&#34;This game was so close to being in my top 10&#34;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Image Courtesy of IGDB&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are all games that I loved, but didn&amp;rsquo;t make my list for some reason. A different me on a different day might have put any of these on the list, but today they fall just short. Here they are in no particular order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wolf Among Us&lt;/strong&gt; – Great story, fantastic game. But it felt short and I want so much more.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Rogue Legacy&lt;/strong&gt; – This is probably the game I come back to the most. It took the horribly unaproachable roguelike genre and made it fun, easy to digest, quick, and fun.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Mario Odyssey&lt;/strong&gt; – Very close to being on my list. As much as I loved it, there was just something missing from Odyssey. A central hub world or more post game content would have made this the perfect Mario game.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Cities Skylines&lt;/strong&gt; – This game perfected the SimCity formula and made it possible to build amazing cities that didn&amp;rsquo;t trend towards &amp;ldquo;New York but different&amp;rdquo;.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Cuphead&lt;/strong&gt; – This game is HARD. Like, I like hard games, as you&amp;rsquo;ll see. But this game is hard. The aesthetics are amazing and the gameplay is smooth. I love it so much but I need to take this game in doses.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Civilization V&lt;/strong&gt; – I love 4X games in general, but I just don&amp;rsquo;t have the hours in my life to dedicate to them. Plus it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be fair to put Civ V in this list since Civ VI is apparently a better game on every level, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t played Civ VI yet.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Fallout New Vegas&lt;/strong&gt; – I made myself only choose one Bethesda game, and Skyrim was more up my alley. If I was 10% more of a post apocalyptic person instead of a fantasy person this would be #5 on my list (spoilers I guess). But New Vegas is so huge and such a great game and I have so much love for it.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Overwatch&lt;/strong&gt; - I loved Overwatch. I did. It was my favorite multiplayer FPS when it came out. I grew up on CS and TF2 and for a non-Valve game to take that spot was amazing. But over time the game has changed and I enjoy It less. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to give any specific reasons, but Overwatch feels less like a wonderland compared to when it came out, and that&amp;rsquo;s okay. It still fills a roll in my life, just less so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;10-ios-games&#34;&gt;10. iOS Games&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;MiniMotor.png&#34; alt=&#34;Mini Motorways&#34; title=&#34;So close to Disaster&#34;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Image Courtesy of Peyton Hable&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I couldn&amp;rsquo;t choose just one game to represent iOS, so I gave it a whole category. In the decade, smartphones really became commonplace and with that, a new way to play games. And smartphone games have been &lt;em&gt;divisive&lt;/em&gt; to say the least. Mobile games went from creative to piles of microtransactions. Currently, mobile games have a rep for being basic, full of timers, and full of ways to accidentally spend a substantial amount of money on digital gems, but a few games really stood out to me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Holedown&lt;/strong&gt; – It&amp;rsquo;s a very simple concept. An endless Breakout-style game, but digging down instead of going up. But the game is so smooth and such a pleasure to play that I just fell in love with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mini Metro and Mini Motorways&lt;/strong&gt; - I know Mini Metro is on other consoles but it feels at home on a phone. And the sequel took so much of what made Mini Metro great and just built on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;iOS ports&lt;/strong&gt; like Stardew Valley, Evoland, Roller Coaster Tycoon, Runescape, Tropico etc. These are all games that made their mark on the PC, and developers were able to fully take advantage of touch controls and make the games feel as smooth on iOS as they felt on consoles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apple Arcade&lt;/strong&gt; – Recently, Apple launched a subscription service with access to more than 100 games. It would take too long to explain all of them, so here is a shortlist of games to try: Sayonara Wildhearts, Mini Motorways (I like it that much I&amp;rsquo;m mentioning it twice, deal with it), Card of Darkness (made by Pendleton Ward, creator of Adventure Time), Outsiders, What the Golf, Assemble with Care, Exit the Gungeon, Oceanhorn 2, there&amp;rsquo;s too many good games to list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;9-mario-maker-2&#34;&gt;9. Mario Maker 2&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;mariomakerpanga.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Mario Maker 2&#34; title=&#34;If you want to torture yourself on an easy Panga level, ID: 837-YQY-91H&#34;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Image Courtesy of US Gamer&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This game was everything I wanted in a 2D Mario game. It had a good campaign, it played great, the mechanics were all there. And there were endless levels that did wild things. I didn&amp;rsquo;t get to play much of the original since it was on a Wii U and no one bought the Wii U, and the 3DS version wasn&amp;rsquo;t a full version.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Mario Maker 2 is something else. The creativity coming out of level creators is amazing. Just watching some good MM2 streamers like Poo, Barb, Dode, Spacekat, etc., and you can see how wild a Mario game can get when you apply a bit of creativity, and more skill than I&amp;rsquo;ll ever have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only reason this isn&amp;rsquo;t higher is because I haven&amp;rsquo;t been able to put enough time into this, and don&amp;rsquo;t have the skill to play the harder levels. I just want to beat a Panga level once in my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;8-magic-arena&#34;&gt;8. Magic Arena&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;Image3_Izzet.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;MTGA_Gameplay&#34; title=&#34;Yes I&#39;m reusing this image. Deal with it.&#34;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Image Courtesy of Wizards of the Coast&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game that &lt;a href=&#34;http://zaza.studio/blog/coming-back-to-magic/&#34;&gt;brought me back into Magic&lt;/a&gt;. I was &lt;del&gt;am&lt;/del&gt; obsessed with Magic and it was really a huge loss for me when I drifted away from playing paper Magic. I have no LGS right now and nowhere to play FNM. I tried Magic Online but I can only handle playing DOS games for so long. Magic Arena is &lt;em&gt;something else&lt;/em&gt;. It is a truly modern Magic game. It plays fantastically. There are bugs but they&amp;rsquo;re minor, at least compared to MTGO. The economic model mostly makes sense and I don&amp;rsquo;t get the feeling of being drained for all the money I have compared to other online TCGs. The game is super playable casually and provides the competitive experience I need. Overall, the only reason this isn&amp;rsquo;t higher is cause of Oko. This is a near perfect game, and I hope as Magic goes on Wizards keeps giving MTGA more love, and crafts Magic to take advantage of such a stellar client.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;7-destiny-2&#34;&gt;7. Destiny 2&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;Destiny2.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Destiny 2&#34; title=&#34;Moon&#39;s Haunted&#34;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Image Courtesy of IGDB&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the game I wanted as a kid. I grew up playing Goldeneye as a small kid, and my very first online experience was Star Wars Battlefront. I also got into Runescape and eventually fell into a pit of Free to Play MMOs. And this whole time, I wanted a game that delivered the kind of consistent world, progression, player bases, and exploration that MMOs had, but as an FPS. Planetside 2 existed, but it wasn&amp;rsquo;t great and it was more a Proto-Battle Royale than a true MMO. Then came Destiny, for the PS3 and Xbox. I didn&amp;rsquo;t have those systems. I watched hungrily at Destiny, wanting to play them, almost buying a PS3 just for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then Destiny 2 was announced for PC. Oh I needed this game. And having played it consistently for over a year, this is everything I wanted. I only wish MMOFPSs were more common, since I feel like there&amp;rsquo;s still so much to explore in this genre. But for me, Destiny 2 (specifically post-Forsaken), was my dream game. And still is. I still play it weekly. Occasionally I binge it hard. This is a game I waited for and dreamed about for over a decade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I kind of built a whole relationship with my girlfriend over this game. So maybe that goes into this being on my list, but it&amp;rsquo;s my list and that&amp;rsquo;s my choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;6-pokemon-swordshield&#34;&gt;6. Pokemon Sword/Shield&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;Pokemon1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Pokemon 1&#34; title=&#34;About to make a big&#34;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Image Courtesy of Peyton Hable&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This game got me back into &lt;del&gt;Magic&lt;/del&gt; Pokemon. I played obsessively from Gen 2 through 4, went back and played Gen 1. I knew every Pokemon up through Gen 4, knew type differences, was getting into IVs and EVs. Then life happened. I never got my hands on a Gen 5 game other than a week borrowing my sis&amp;rsquo;, and before I knew it Gen 5, 6, and 7 all passed me by. Holy shit I missed out on almost half the Pokemon games made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So when I got Sword, I was nervous. The snippets I played of Gens 5-7 weren&amp;rsquo;t fantastic. I felt like parts of the game I loved were taken out or simplified. And starting Sword, I felt that too. But then I started seeing Sword for what it is. A game designed for a modern player. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t 12 anymore. I didn&amp;rsquo;t have 4 hours after school to just ride my bike around Victory Road leveling my Pokemon individually. All the things &amp;ldquo;making the game easier&amp;rdquo; were quality of life changes that kept me playing. I could tweak my team at any point. I didn&amp;rsquo;t have to spend hours leveling my team, I instead can spend that time playing the story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;Pokemon2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Pokemon 2&#34; title=&#34;is big&#34;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Image Courtesy of Peyton Hable&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And to balance the Quality of Life changes, they added challenge to so many other parts. The Gyms are so creative, and the Gym leaders are tough. The Wild Area is the Safari Zone perfected. The fact that you can face a level 50 Pokemon coming out of your first town really makes the Pokemon world feel like a world. It was no longer a fully linear game. This feels like a world people and Pokemon live in. And the whole game has not only made me fall in love with Pokemon all over again, and provide me a game I can play while working full-time and feel fully fulfilled, but it also provided a gateway for my partner, who has never played a Pokemon game, to come in and understand the wild complex world of Pokemon and fall in love with it too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;5-the-elder-scrolls-v-skyrim&#34;&gt;5. The Elder Scrolls V: Skyrim&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;Skyrim.png&#34; alt=&#34;Skyrim&#34; title=&#34;I don&#39;t know how many times I&#39;m gonna end up giving Bethesda money for this fucking game&#34;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Image Courtesy of IGDB&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What can I say about Skyrim that hasn&amp;rsquo;t already been said before. This game changed Western RPGs. It took a recipe that was introduced in Morrowind, and improved in Oblivion, and perfected it. By perfect I mean this is still a pile of bugs, but a nice one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Skyrim succeeded where Oblivion failed I think mostly cause it&amp;rsquo;s pretty. It&amp;rsquo;s hard to convince someone to play a game that looks odd. Skyrim succeeded in creating a game that gamers were immediately attracted to. And once gamers started playing, it opened up an entire world that you could put 300+ hours into it (without Mods) and still not discover everything. It created a world of memes (Arrow Knee lol) and it exposed a lot of gamers who were used to linear games to a truly open world game. You could put 150 hours into the game and not touch the main story. Or you can complete the main story in 20 hours. The game gives you the freedom to completely ignore the main story and fully enjoy everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And every Western RPG, along with a few JRPGs (I&amp;rsquo;ll get to that) have been heavily inspired by Skyrim, taken lessons from it, and it&amp;rsquo;s really expanded on the genre. The Witcher Series is definitely one that benefit from Skyrim existing. And Skyrim is a game I come back and play often. I played it around the time it came out. And over the years I&amp;rsquo;ve probably played it a half a dozen times as different saves, doing completely different things, exploring different worlds, and never having a real repeated experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that&amp;rsquo;s before the wild, amazing mod community that exists on PC. You can get mods to improve quality of life like &lt;em&gt;a map that works as a map&lt;/em&gt; or better menus, you can get texture mods to make the game way prettier. You can get mods to add new quests, storylines, weapons, enemies, clothing, etc. Yes there&amp;rsquo;s even a mod to do that, get your mind out of the gutter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only reason Skyrim isn&amp;rsquo;t higher is cause, well, it&amp;rsquo;s a buggy mess. Even with years of patches, tons of unofficial patches, DLC, everything, it is still full of bugs. And Skyrim has that weird way of having endearing bugs. Most other games, bugs are horrible and run the game. In Skyrim, they&amp;rsquo;re still bugs, but they have a kind of fun around them most games don’t. Most people who were heavily on the internet in 2011-2013ish knows those videos where you see a horse climbing a vertical wall on a mountain, or taking one step and dying, or clipping, or having characters be where they never should be. And while it made it fun, it can be tedious when autosave puts you in an impossible place and you&amp;rsquo;re stuck dying cause of some weird bug.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;4-virtual-reality&#34;&gt;4. Virtual Reality&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;WillVR.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Virtual Reality&#34; title=&#34;I had to include this pic&#34;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Image Courtesy of Will Smith (not that one)&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another category, not so much cause I can&amp;rsquo;t pick a game, but because I haven&amp;rsquo;t had much time to play VR. In this decade, VR came back from the dead, from a curiosity you&amp;rsquo;d find in a Disney World arcade, to something that anyone &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; have in their homes. The first time I tried VR, it changed my life. I&amp;rsquo;ve only been able to use it a handful of times, but each time has cemented in me how important VR is. But if I had to pick a game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;beatsaber.png&#34; alt=&#34;Destiny 2&#34; title=&#34;Don&#39;t play Hard on your first go. Just... dont.&#34;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Image Courtesy of IGDB&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beat Saber – Enough has been written about this. Honestly, the best description of &amp;ldquo;Guitar Hero with Lightsabers&amp;rdquo; will never be enough. Watch gameplays, or find &lt;em&gt;anywhere&lt;/em&gt; that does VR demos and try it. It&amp;rsquo;s worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-celeste&#34;&gt;3. Celeste&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;Celeste.png&#34; alt=&#34;Celeste&#34; title=&#34;This section is honestly scary&#34;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Image Courtesy of IGDB&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This game had everything I loved. Tricky platforming. A lot of skill. Rewarding gameplay. A killer soundtrack. And a story that hit me just the right way. When Celeste came out, I was a bit lost. A lot had happened in my life, and here comes such a perfect game about overcoming obstacles, and finding yourself along the way. I do not want to give away any more of the story, but for a game I maybe put 20 hours into, I think about it constantly. It gave me hope. It inspired me. It challenged me. And as someone who is &lt;em&gt;terrible&lt;/em&gt; at completing games, I completed this one multiple times. Just gameplay alone this deserves to be in my top 10, add in the story and it&amp;rsquo;s honestly very close to being my number 1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-portal-2&#34;&gt;2. Portal 2&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;Portal2.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Portal 2&#34; title=&#34;it me&#34;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Image Courtesy of IGDB&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Portal was the first game that really got me to say &amp;ldquo;wait, you can do that with a game?&amp;rdquo; It was a nearly perfect game, and honestly the reason I got into PC gaming. A few months before Portal 2 was released, Portal 1 was made free and I ended up getting a graphics card for my parents&amp;rsquo; desktop just to be able to play it. Then Portal 2 came out and I put &lt;em&gt;way to many hours into it&lt;/em&gt;. This game took everything that made Portal great, took out and changed the few pain points that existed, and crafted a beautiful story in the universe they already created.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Portal 2&amp;rsquo;s story was so great. It expanded this &amp;ldquo;Science lab&amp;rdquo; into this massive pseudo-government operation run by essentially a very angry J.K. Simmons, and created a truly human story with very non-human creatures. You felt for GLaDOS. She wasn&amp;rsquo;t just some crazy machine anymore. She was a tragic character. You feel for Wheatley and his quest, you fall in love with the story between &lt;del&gt;J. Jonah Jameson&lt;/del&gt; Cave Johnson and GLaDOS. The game&amp;rsquo;s story is told in such an unorthodox way, and at times it feels like you&amp;rsquo;re along for the ride in someone else&amp;rsquo;s story. But even then, Portal doesn&amp;rsquo;t stop delivering magic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Co-op campaign is completely separate from the main game and could have been its own game. While the storyline is more simple, the way the puzzles are designed to be played by two players without each player being bored is amazing. And this is the best test for Communication in a relationship let me tell you that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-the-legend-of-zelda-breath-of-the-wild&#34;&gt;1. The Legend of Zelda: Breath of the Wild&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This game got me back into &lt;del&gt;Magic&lt;/del&gt; &lt;del&gt;Pokemon&lt;/del&gt; Zelda. Oh my god there&amp;rsquo;s a trend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;BotW3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Zelda 1&#34; title=&#34;WHEEEEEEEEE&#34;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Image Courtesy of me :)&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Breath of the Wild is what happens when you have 20+ years to polish the Legend of Zelda formula, 10 years to polish the Skyrim formula, and combine them absolutely perfectly. BotW might as well be a sequel to Skyrim, it borrows so much from it. You&amp;rsquo;re given a short tutorial, and then essentially faced with an open world with essentially a &amp;ldquo;you can go this way if you want, but I&amp;rsquo;m not the boss of you&amp;rdquo;. If you wanted to leave the starting area and immediately go fight Ganon, you can. If you want to collect every single Korok Seed, you can. If you just wanna sled down the tallest mountain and get sicccc air, you can. The game gives you absolute freedom. The world is the Zelda world. All the monsters you love are there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the gameplay from the 3D Zeldas&amp;rsquo; have been refined to where the combat feels great. The game, instead of punishing you from diverting from the main story, rewards you for exploring. The main plot of the game is always there, and you don&amp;rsquo;t lose your way how you would with Skyrim. And the word I keep coming back to, polish, is everywhere. While Skyrim is a Boogeyman of bugs that somehow learned to walk, Zelda is truly a Nintendo game. The seams are always never visible. The game has a reason for almost everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;BotW1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Zelda 1&#34; title=&#34;Looking out, every point that looks interesting has a reason to explore.&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got this game in a time of my life where I had almost no time for games. And somehow I put hours upon hours into it. The game never felt dull. There was always something to do, somewhere to explore. You&amp;rsquo;d find somewhere on the map that you think the game devs would ignore cause &lt;em&gt;who would go there&lt;/em&gt; and there&amp;rsquo;s a physics challenge there. Or there&amp;rsquo;s a powerful enemy. Or a shrine. Or a Korok. Every single corner of this game was lovingly crafted in a way to provide the best gameplay experience I&amp;rsquo;ve ever had. I come back to this game not with guilt or shame that I&amp;rsquo;ve been away or not finished the story, but with joy and excitement to explore. Dungeons I thought were impossible I&amp;rsquo;m coming back to. I&amp;rsquo;m going to areas I wrote off a year ago. This game has so much in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that&amp;rsquo;s without factoring in the DLC. Nintendo has done a fantastic job of creating DLC that expands the game without taking away what makes the game magical. The DLC doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel forced, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel like a cash grab. And it doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel like Nintendo is charging extra for the full experience. It is a nice addition to the game that make the game better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only pause I have for BotW is the lack of Overworld/Dungeon and the slight repetitiveness of shrines. One of my favorite parts of old Zelda games was clearing dungeons and solving puzzles. And this game didn&amp;rsquo;t really have much of that, other than the Divine Beasts. But the game more than made up for it with it&amp;rsquo;s expansive Overworld, easily the best overworld of any Zelda game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;BotW2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Zelda 1&#34; title=&#34;Running around, maybe you see a giant Shadow of the Colossus monster&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This game honestly helped me love games again. At a time I was jaded at games and Triple A games in general, and Breath of the Wild gave me hope that people are still crafting games with love. Breath of the Wild is my game of the decade, and honestly the best game I have ever played.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Footnote: Before anyone complains about me not talking about [insert game here], this list is all games that I have played. It&amp;rsquo;s not a definitive list and definitely not meant to be &amp;ldquo;the best games ever&amp;rdquo;. Just the games that impacted me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a list of games that might have made my list if I played them, but &lt;em&gt;time exists&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GTA V&lt;br&gt;
The Last of Us&lt;br&gt;
Mass Effect (any)&lt;br&gt;
Dark Souls (genre)&lt;br&gt;
Witcher 3&lt;br&gt;
Outer Worlds&lt;br&gt;
Spider-Man PS4&lt;br&gt;
Bioshock Infinite&lt;br&gt;
Red Dead (either really)&lt;br&gt;
Baba is You&lt;br&gt;
Life is Strange&lt;br&gt;
4X Games - I love the genre but any one game is dedicating my life to it.&lt;br&gt;
Firewatch&lt;br&gt;
That one game you&amp;rsquo;re mad about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Emmanuel Medina&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Emmanuel Medina is a musician, gamer, and Magic player from Southern California.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iOS Game Reviews: Elder Scrolls Blades</title>
      <link>https://zaza.studio/archive/ios-review-es-blades/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zaza.studio/archive/ios-review-es-blades/</guid>
      <description>I want to love Elder Scrolls: Blades. I do. I really really do.
I&amp;rsquo;m starting this off by saying that I am a huge fan of the Elder Scrolls series. I have put more hours than I can count into Oblivion and almost as many into Skyrim. Elder Scrolls Online is in my top 5 MMOs. So I wanted, so desperately, for a mobile game to capture the feeling of Elder Scrolls.</description>
      <content>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to love Elder Scrolls: Blades. I do. I really really do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;es-title.png&#34; alt=&#34;Title Screen - I wish it lived up to the hype of seeing this page&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m starting this off by saying that I am a huge fan of the Elder Scrolls series. I have put more hours than I can count into Oblivion and almost as many into Skyrim. Elder Scrolls Online is in my top 5 MMOs. So I wanted, so desperately, for a mobile game to capture the feeling of Elder Scrolls. The massive world, the progression, the sense of exploration, the feeling of almost endless depth (even if that depth is almost irrelevant to the actual game).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This game. Does not. Do that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lets start with what the game is. It is a mobile RPG for iOS and Android. You come back from being exiled as a member of the Blades to find your hometown destroyed. There are three game modes, Town, Abyss, and Arena. The gameplay is similar in all of them. It is a 3D First Person RPG, like Skyrim, ESO, and the Elder Scrolls games in the past. You move by tapping the ground to the location you&amp;rsquo;ll be walking towards. If you go into combat, it focuses in on the enemy and you tap and hold to attack, or click icons to use Magic or Ranged attacks. You can collect items in dungeons by tapping them, or talk to people, again, by tapping on them. A huge aspect of the game is rebuilding a city that was destroyed, in true ES fashion by Magic, by collecting in game currency and resources. Before we even get to the story, or the freemium aspects of Blades, or the game modes, I have to talk about the controls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;controls&#34;&gt;Controls&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;Movement.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Yes, people turn exactly like that irl&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this game in many points feels like it was built from the ground up to be a mobile game, it feels like it was built by people who have never played a mobile game. The game can be played both vertically and horizontally. Vertically, swiping on the screen will allow you to look around. Tapping on the ground will move your character. Horizontally this still works, but swiping on what feels like the bottom left 1/8th of the screen will allow you to walk like an analog stick, and swiping on the bottom right 1/8th will move the screen like a right analog stick. This isn&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;bad&lt;/em&gt; per se, but it leads to awkwardness.
The movement with tapping feels far worse than with the virtual analog stick. When tapping on the ground to move, the game will automatically take control of the camera, sometimes hilariously badly. Walking up stairs, the actual view you have is terrible, looking up about 45 degrees, and when you reach the top of the stairs your view stays in that position. If you click something around a corner, the character will strafe in a very unusual way around the corner. It &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; something you can get used to, but definitely annoying. It&amp;rsquo;s definitely more of a “get used to” issue, but still feels like an oversight by the game devs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, in landscape, the game plays very well. The movement is smooth when using the virtual joysticks. Your character feels like he’s actually moving. The camera moves a tad slow but it feels a lot more natural horizontally than vertically. It kind of gives this game a feeling like the vertical mode/one hand mode was added way later in development, and the devs didn’t quite know what to do with a mobile game. Movement can be a bit awkward but is something you can get used to. What I couldn&amp;rsquo;t get used to was the combat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;combat&#34;&gt;Combat&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;Combat.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Pop the bubble&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Combat is where this game fully stops feeling like an Elder Scrolls game. You tap and hold to charge an attack, and let go to release it. If you release &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; when the charging circle gets to its ready indicator, you get a critical hit. You also get buttons on the screen for using abilities and Magic. However, it is a far cry from an actual Elder Scrolls game, where you move, run, use abilities, attack, block, and (in Skyrim) using Shouts. Most fights usually end up being “can you tap correctly” and “are you stronger than the enemy” and that’s it. Any depth is lost in the lack of responsiveness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;story&#34;&gt;Story&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;story.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Nothing to see here&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you launch the game, you get a quick instance where your character is introduced. In traditional Elder Scrolls fashion, &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; happened and you’re starting life from scratch. Unlike riding a cart to your death, or waking up in a prison, you’re heading home because you were a member of the “Blades” a kind of Secret Service in Tamriel that got disbanded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You defeat a few mercenaries and make your way to town. &lt;em&gt;Because Elder Scrolls&lt;/em&gt; and there having to be some supernatural disaster, the town is destroyed. Then the actual game starts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides this, there are quest missions that further your personal story, discovering who you were and with backstory on what happened to the Blades, as well as insight into the town and the magic beneath it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;town&#34;&gt;Town&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;es-town.png&#34; alt=&#34;Fix me please&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Town is the Main game mode in ES: Blades. You will go on Quests to rescue town members, or to do tasks that those town members need done (Kill Goblins, Collect Resources, etc.), and get gold and resources that will then help you rebuild the Town. There is a lot to do in the town. You are tasked with rebuilding important buildings like the Blacksmith or Alchemist, which will unlock shops and new weapons/items. And, because this is a mobile Freemium game, the first few buildings are fairly cheap to build, and the price goes up fairly quickly from there, requiring way more time and resources to rebuild. There is also a “Jobs” board that has quests on them, including a Daily and Weekly Quest that has better rewards. These jobs will also drop you into a dungeon instance, just like the quests from town members.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The actual instances are where I feel the game really falling apart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;dungeons&#34;&gt;Dungeons&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have so much to say about the dungeons, but I’ll start with this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay that’s a low blow. I’ll be nicer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dungeons are all more or less the same. They are a set of twisting hallways and rectangular rooms. The dungeons are mostly linear, you walk through the dungeon, kill the NPCs, break some breakables(usually pots), find a few chests, get to the end, rinse, repeat. And this is where I feel the game starts falling apart and you see it for what it is, not an Elder Scrolls game, but just another mobile Freemium game. There is no interesting dungeon design. There are no puzzles. There’s no feeling like you’re in a natural environment. Caves don’t feel like caves, hideouts don’t feel like hideouts. It all feels like randomly twisting passages into random rooms. Besides occasional staircases, the map is more or less flat. While you can say this is a consideration for being a mobile game, there’s plenty of unexplored space on how you can make an interesting dungeon fit for mobile games, instead of just boiling down the formula used on main ES games into its most basic elements, then creating a map that doesn’t even approach a game from 1993s in terms of being interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You get a certain amount of decent quests a day so even dungeoneering kinda has a limited lifespan. You go through the dungeon, endure clunky combat, and get rewards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;abyss&#34;&gt;Abyss&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of Dungeons, an actual interesting new feature of ES: Blades is the Abyss. The Abyss is a Rogue-lite game mode where a dungeon is randomly generated and you have to fight your way through it. I was &lt;em&gt;so excited&lt;/em&gt; for this game mode because I love rogue-like and rogue-lite games. Rogue Legacy is one of my favorite games, and I’ve put more hours than I’d like to admit into NetHack. This. Isn’t that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You end up going through a randomly snaking passage into 1-2 rooms. Clear out the NPC enemies, and then you make your way through more passageways till you reach a stairway to make your way down to the next level. And repeat. Enemies get harder as you go down, and every 5 levels it saves your progress so when you go in, you can resume from that level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I talked about how much I loved rogue likes. However, this game fully falls on its face and this game mode feels as half baked as the rest of the game. The levels of the dungeon are short. Like… painfully short. I understand that it is a mobile game but they’re short for that. {this can change, revise this}[The enemies feel squishy. There is very little challenge when it comes to the actual combat in the Abyss]. There is little to no exploration, since the actual game mode is about as linear as possible. There’s nothing to discover going down the Abyss. And it feels more like a game of attrition than anything else. How long can you last till your health is drained. That’s it. The Abyss is, in my mind, a great idea for an Elder Scrolls game. No matter how big the ES world is, there’s only so many dungeons Bethesda can design, and having an endless randomly generated dungeon is a great idea. But the lack of interesting anything, lack of complexity, and clunky feel has this feeling like the rest of the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ambiance-and-feel&#34;&gt;Ambiance and Feel&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, Elder Scrolls: Blades feels like an Elder Scrolls game without any soul. The Town feels like a generic high fantasy village. There’s not much distinct there that makes it feel like it’s anywhere in Tamriel. A lot of the icons just feel lifted from Oblivion or Skyrim. The town itself might have been made to look generic because it is to be decorated by the players, but even then it feels closer to a generic iOS game than something that belongs in an Elder Scrolls game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The skill system is expanive, and in the time I&amp;rsquo;ve played I haven&amp;rsquo;t gotten to go too far down it, but it&amp;rsquo;s definitely one of the more polished parts of the game, and feels like the one part you can really plan out progression related to the non-city aspects in the game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dungeons look samey. This has always been an issue in the ES games, but at least on main releases there were puzzles or challenges, or different, non-linear designs to hold the dungeons up. These feel about as generic as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The music feels like a bad cover band’s version of Skyrim’s music. It fits the tropes of Fantasy music. It is “epic”, feels like its in a minor key to have some somber moments but still “uplifting”. It’s full of strings. But it just feels like generic music.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fact that the game is instanced, while it is definitely necessary for a mobile game, pulls you out of the game itself. And when part of the selling point of every Elder Scrolls game before this &lt;em&gt;was&lt;/em&gt; immersion, I feel like this is a big step back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;looking-forward&#34;&gt;Looking Forward&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It looks like Bethesda is listening though. Between when I started writing this review and right before it went out, I got this push notificaiton.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;notification.png&#34; alt=&#34;I thought I had notifications turned off&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They are actively trying to do things to make it feel less freemium. This is something I would never expect from a company like(and I hate to pick on them cause they make good games) Supercell. They&amp;rsquo;ve also added confirmation screens for spending any large amount of gems(over 11 says their patch notes) and changed percentages on chest drops. This is good news that Bethesda is listening and this game is more than the cash grab it felt like at the beginning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is also the Arena coming soon. Where ES: Blades players can fight against each other. The Arena may be a very good reason for more competitive players. I&amp;rsquo;m personally not too keen on PvP on mobile, mostly cause the chances I get for mobile games are maybe a few minutes on the toilet at work, But the option is there, and combat between players I would expect to both feel more natural and actually be more engaging than combat with NPCs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;final-thoughts&#34;&gt;Final Thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly, if this game was not an Elder Scrolls game, I would have just ignored it in the app store as another freemium game trying to make a quick buck. It has all the trappings of freemium games, multiple game modes that all rely on timers; a limited amount of short, semi-interesting engaging sections(Jobs/Quests) that you need to wait real world time to reappear, a chest system that takes real world time to open, with the option of paying real world money to speed up. The gameplay is just engaging enough to keep playing, and the city building hits all the right spots for me. But even just two weeks after it&amp;rsquo;s released, I find myself reaching for other games on my phone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since this is my first review, I had to figure out how I&amp;rsquo;m gonna rate games. I think an out of Five system works well, especially for iOS games since there&amp;rsquo;s such a range of games, and experience, that anything more granular feels like it&amp;rsquo;d be too specific to be useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;elder-scrolls-blades---35&#34;&gt;Elder Scrolls: Blades - 3/5&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disclaimer: ES: Blades is in Beta/Early Access and a lot is subject to change. I will add a section about Arena below the final score in an edit once it is released&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-good&#34;&gt;The Good&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Semi-engaging gameplay&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interesting city building aspect&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Decent graphics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s an Elder Scrolls Game. On your phone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Runs very smooth, even on an iPhone 7&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-bad&#34;&gt;The Bad&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clunky Movement when not using Virtual Joysticks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Over-reliance on Freemium aspects like timers on chests and buildings, gems, and quest refresh&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Uninspired music and visuals that would fit basically any fantasy game, none really feeling Elder Scrolls like&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Weak Combat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Difficult to play in short bursts, not enough content for longer gameplay&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Review by Emmanuel Medina&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
