<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>personal on Critical Point</title>
    <link>https://zaza.studio/categories/personal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in personal on Critical Point</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://zaza.studio/categories/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Yearly Theme 2021: Year of Discovery</title>
      <link>https://zaza.studio/p/yearly-theme-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zaza.studio/p/yearly-theme-2021/</guid>
      <description>So, 2020 sucked. I have been doing yearly themes since I believe 2015 and 2020 is the only year where I completely lost track of my theme. I don&amp;rsquo;t think I need to go into why covid but it&amp;rsquo;s time to get back on the train.
So for 2021, I am doing a 180 from the life I led in 2020. Last year might as well have been &amp;ldquo;the Year of Lockdown&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Darkroom Diary: iPhone Photography, and Finding Photography Again</title>
      <link>https://zaza.studio/p/iphone-photography/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zaza.studio/p/iphone-photography/</guid>
      <description>I was very into photography a few years ago. Decent DSLR, lenses, accessories, the whole deal. But for various reasons my love of photography left me. The camera was too heavy to bring, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t good enough, and I had some personal reasons. So I kinda stopped photography. The DSLR was sold off. My film camera is in a box somewhere. It all just&amp;hellip; stopped.
That changed when I got my iPhone 11.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2019: Year of Content</title>
      <link>https://zaza.studio/p/2019-yearly-theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zaza.studio/p/2019-yearly-theme/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about my 2019 plan for a while. And after the absolute failure that 2018: Year of Less was, but also the kinda semi success of 2017: Year of Completion, and the success of my 2016: Year of Me, I was excited to talk about my new theme. Also New Years Resolutions are dumb.
Part of the reason I started this blog is to chronicle my yearly themes. I&amp;rsquo;ll probably repost my old themes but no promises.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accidental Disconnect from the Internet</title>
      <link>https://zaza.studio/p/disconnect/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zaza.studio/p/disconnect/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been an odd month or two for me. For the first time in as long as I can remember, I&amp;rsquo;ve been mostly disconnected from the internet.
This wasn&amp;rsquo;t really any kind of planned event. I had recently become more active on the Do By Friday discord, was fairly active with my bands social media, rediscovered Twitter a third time, and was actually enjoying Instagram. Then, shortly before I took my trip to Mexico, my use basically plummited.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coming Back to Magic</title>
      <link>https://zaza.studio/p/state-of-magic-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zaza.studio/p/state-of-magic-2018/</guid>
      <description>I left Magic about two years ago. It was a slow fade, and once I was done I thought I was out. I thought I quit this Cardboard Crack
OH NO
You don&amp;rsquo;t just leave Magic.
And I&amp;rsquo;m so glad I&amp;rsquo;m back.
Backstory. I stopped playing Magic about two years ago mostly due to money and time. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t justify the entry fee, or the time commitment every Friday. So I stopped going.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
