<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>darkroom diary on critical point</title>
    <link>https://emmaceleste.gay/categories/darkroom-diary/</link>
    <description>Recent content in darkroom diary on critical point</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://emmaceleste.gay/categories/darkroom-diary/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Darkroom Diary: Using a $35 Lens on a 10 Year Old Camera</title>
      <link>https://emmaceleste.gay/posts/darkroom-diary-35-dollar-lens/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://emmaceleste.gay/posts/darkroom-diary-35-dollar-lens/</guid>
      <description>Photography is an expensive hobby. It&amp;rsquo;s one I love but definitely will suck as much money as you put into it. So when I see a lens that costs $35 on Amazon, I know I need to get it immediately.
Taken with iPhone 11
Fotasy 35mm f/1.6 Micro 4/3 Lens The lens I picked up is the Fotasy 35mm f/1.6 lens. It&amp;rsquo;s Micro 4/3 lens so it&amp;rsquo;s a 70mm equivalent. That&amp;rsquo;s a bit tight for pure street photography but I should be able to make it work.</description>
      <content>&lt;p&gt;Photography is an expensive hobby. It&amp;rsquo;s one I love but definitely will suck as much money as you put into it. So when I see a lens that costs $35 on Amazon, I know I need to get it immediately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;fotasy-lens.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Fotasy Lens&#34;&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Taken with iPhone 11&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fotasy-35mm-f16-micro-43-lens&#34;&gt;Fotasy 35mm &lt;em&gt;f&lt;/em&gt;/1.6 Micro 4/3 Lens&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lens I picked up is the Fotasy 35mm &lt;em&gt;f&lt;/em&gt;/1.6 lens. It&amp;rsquo;s Micro 4/3 lens so it&amp;rsquo;s a 70mm equivalent. That&amp;rsquo;s a bit tight for pure street photography but I should be able to make it work. And it should be great for portraits. &amp;ldquo;Should&amp;rdquo;. More on that in a bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lens itself feels solid. It is made of metal, which I definitely didn&amp;rsquo;t expect for a lens that cost $35. The lens felt pretty damn sharp on my camera&amp;rsquo;s screen, but when I reviewed the images I got a different story. It&amp;rsquo;s definitely a lot sharper than you&amp;rsquo;d expect out of a $35 lens. It&amp;rsquo;s not a Holga, but it is a far cry from more expensive lenses. I was expecting something like a toy camera lens but this is almost useable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;bokeh.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;BOKEH&#34;&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;This lens does have some killer Bokeh&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The interesting thing about the lens is that the aperture is stepless. There&amp;rsquo;s no clicks at any &lt;em&gt;f&lt;/em&gt;-stop,m. There&amp;rsquo;s definitely a freedom to this. If I want to open the aperture &lt;em&gt;slightly&lt;/em&gt; more than &lt;em&gt;f&lt;/em&gt;/8 without going all the way to &lt;em&gt;f&lt;/em&gt;/5.6, I easily can. It makes you think a lot more about your shots. I believe this kind of aperture is more common on video lenses. However, the softness of the lens doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to lend itself to video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are trade-offs of course. The lens is fully manual. There&amp;rsquo;s no electronics in it whatsoever. There is no autofocus. If you&amp;rsquo;re trying to shoot sports, animals, or children this is not the lens for you. But if you&amp;rsquo;re able to take a second to frame and focus your shot this lens might be what you&amp;rsquo;re looking for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;bike.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Bike&#34;&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;It took me a while to get used to a 70mm equivalent lens. Can you tell I normally shoot wide?&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, it is still a $35 lens. Mine came with what could be a design choice or a defect. Most likely defect. The focus ring turns about an 1/8 of a turn past infinity. So if you&amp;rsquo;re shooting from the hip that might lead to lost shots. I &lt;em&gt;cannot trust&lt;/em&gt; this lens to zone focus. I don&amp;rsquo;t know if this is an issue with my lens specifically or with this lens in general but it is something to talk about. There&amp;rsquo;s also slight resistance and grating in the focus ring around infinity. Not major, but something you feel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;image-quality-and-experience&#34;&gt;Image Quality and Experience&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ended up rewriting this whole section once I viewed my images on my computer. On my cameras tiny screen, the pictures looked sharp and in focus and I thought I was getting great shots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The image quality on this lens is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; great. It has a very soft feel, even when focused at &lt;em&gt;f&lt;/em&gt;/16. The image quality reminds me of a mediocre film point and shoot. And that I might not be a bad thing if that&amp;rsquo;s what you&amp;rsquo;re looking for. The lens has some pretty bad vignetting, and in some images it actually ruins the shot. I could see taking shots with this, running it through some VSCO filters and getting a really nice film feel. But this should not be your main lens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;missed-shot.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Missed Shot&#34;&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;I focused to infinity for this shot. But since the lens is defective and goes past infinity, the shot was missed. This isn&amp;rsquo;t the only shot I missed, and I&amp;rsquo;m not proud of it, but something anyone considering this lens should think about.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I did like about this lens is how tiny it is. Like, it&amp;rsquo;s small. It&amp;rsquo;s not quite a pancake lens but it&amp;rsquo;s almost there. It&amp;rsquo;s about 3/4 the size of the kit lens when the kit lens is closed, and less than 1/2 the size of the fully extended kit lens. And for me, that&amp;rsquo;s a completely new experience. The majority of my experience with cameras comes from a Nikon d3300 and its lenses. And I can&amp;rsquo;t help but think of the tele on that and comparing it to this tiny thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the focal length, I am shooting on Micro 4/3, which means this 35mm lens acts more like a 70mm. This is a change for me because I normally like shooting a lot wider. My last post was literally gushing over the iPhone 11&amp;rsquo;s 13mm equivalent lens. So it was a full 180 for me. But it gives me another perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;portrait.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Portrait&#34;&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Probably my favorite shot with this lens. However, this lens is too soft to take real portraits with.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lens ends up acting a bit like a portrait lens on my camera. And that kind of makes the softness of the lens hurt a bit more. 70mm is such a good portrait lens and the way subjects look is honestly incredible, but I won&amp;rsquo;t really be able to use it for that if my subjects won&amp;rsquo;t come out sharp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;using-a-10-year-old-mirrorless&#34;&gt;Using a 10 Year Old Mirrorless&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this has been the most surprising part of the whole experience to be quite honest. I&amp;rsquo;m using an Olympus PEN E-PL1. This is a camera that came out 10 years ago in 2010. In the world of digital, to use even a year old camera isn&amp;rsquo;t seen well, let alone a camera from the previous decade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it&amp;rsquo;s been great. The camera accepted the lens immediately and I was able to shoot right after mounting it. This was actually a big concern for me since I saw so many reviews about needing to dig through settings to allow cameras to accept a fully manual lens. But no, it worked right away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;pipes.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Pipes&#34;&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;My camera metered the light perfectly every time. I just wish this lens didn&amp;rsquo;t suck. You don&amp;rsquo;t see sharpness at any point of this shot.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course autofocus and camera controlled aperture don&amp;rsquo;t work. It &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; a manual lens. But with the camera on P, it does a pretty phenomenal job of metering the light and choosing the right ISO and shutter speed for the shot. In terms of light metering, I haven&amp;rsquo;t had a miss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are definitely features I wish I had. The E-PL1 has no focus peaking. So focus has to either be intuition or zooming in with the screen on the back. And I&amp;rsquo;ve definitely missed shots like that. But that&amp;rsquo;s part of the fun of a manual lens. If I wanted shots to be perfectly focused every time I&amp;rsquo;d just use my kit lens at &lt;em&gt;f&lt;/em&gt;16.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And of course a 12MP 10 year old sensor isn&amp;rsquo;t exactly cutting edge right now. The ISO is useable only down to about 800. ISO 1600 is pushing it and ISO 3200 is a noisy mess. This is especially challenging to work with on a lens that&amp;rsquo;s already pretty soft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hadn&amp;rsquo;t been able to put this lens down. And I think that&amp;rsquo;s the most important thing. Since I got this lens it&amp;rsquo;s just lived on my camera. It&amp;rsquo;s fun, it&amp;rsquo;s interesting, it&amp;rsquo;s kinda odd and unique and finicky and sometimes bad. Often bad. It&amp;rsquo;s imperfect. In my first draft of this article I praised that imperfection. After seeing my shots I think that praise was a bit early.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;kiah.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Kiah&#34;&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;I had to include a picture of dog.&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I wanted a lens that helped me shoot more. I could have saved for months and spent $1000 on a wonderful prime. But $35 and two days of shipping and I&amp;rsquo;m shooting now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, buy a $35 lens, expect $35 lens quality.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Darkroom Diary: iPhone Photography, and Finding Photography Again</title>
      <link>https://emmaceleste.gay/posts/iphone-photography/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://emmaceleste.gay/posts/iphone-photography/</guid>
      <description>editors note: lol. lmao. this is cute past emma. where you&amp;rsquo;re going, you dont need pixels.
I was very into photography a few years ago. Decent DSLR, lenses, accessories, the whole deal. But for various reasons my love of photography left me. The camera was too heavy to bring, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t good enough, and I had some personal reasons. So I kinda stopped photography. The DSLR was sold off. My film camera is in a box somewhere.</description>
      <content>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;editors note: lol. lmao. this is cute past emma. where you&amp;rsquo;re going, you dont need pixels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was very into photography a few years ago. Decent DSLR, lenses, accessories, the whole deal. But for various reasons my love of photography left me. The camera was too heavy to bring, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t good enough, and I had some personal reasons. So I kinda stopped photography. The DSLR was sold off. My film camera is in a box somewhere. It all just&amp;hellip; stopped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That changed when I got my iPhone 11.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;ranchfire.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Ranch Fire&#34;&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Ranch Fire in Socal 2020&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Swapping to this phone, it genuinely feels like I can just pull my phone out and get the shot I want. My phone feels like a standalone camera while in the camera app. AND I HAVE A WIDE ANGLE LENS. Sure your 300mm lens is cool, a nifty 50mm is a delight to shoot with, but give me something under 24mm any day. And the wide angle is a 13mm equivalent. &lt;em&gt;Yes. Please.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lemme go over the specs real quick before I get into why I&amp;rsquo;m going back to shooting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;camera-specs&#34;&gt;Camera Specs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;cameras.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;iPhone Camera&#34;&gt;
&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Taken with iPhone 10&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The iPhone 11 has two cameras in it. The 11 Pro has three. The regular camera is a 12MP 26mm equivalent, the wide angle is a 13mm equivalent, and the telephoto in the Pro is a 52mm equivalent. All with built in optical stabilization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But specs are just specs. My DSLR from a few years ago had a higher pixel count, better autofocus, and was APS-C so I didn&amp;rsquo;t have to rely on software tricks to get things like Bokeh or shallow depth of field. It was a better camera spec wise. But there&amp;rsquo;s a reason I&amp;rsquo;m taking more pictures with my phone now than I did with my DSLR back then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;shoot-with-the-camera-you-have&#34;&gt;Shoot with the Camera you Have&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;fence.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Chain Link Fence&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the first advice you will receive as a photographer. The best camera in the world is the one you have with you. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if you own multi-thousand dollar cameras and lenses, if your camera is stuck at home and you miss shots, that gear might as well not exist. This obviously is a particularly strong pro to the iPhone, since basically no one leaves their home without their phone anymore. And this isn&amp;rsquo;t just a plus for the iPhone, &lt;em&gt;almost any&lt;/em&gt; phone camera is able to take phenomenal photos&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But beyond that, the iPhone 11 allowing me to have essentially two different lenses to get different shots allows me to take pictures I otherwise wouldn&amp;rsquo;t. There&amp;rsquo;s no need to think &amp;ldquo;do I need to bring my 12mm and my 35mm&amp;rdquo; if I have both right in my pocket. And in general, no matter where I go I don&amp;rsquo;t need to feel bad about leaving my big camera at home if I have something in my pocket for almost any situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;does-it-bring-joy&#34;&gt;Does it Bring Joy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thing is, most of that last section could apply to my iPhone 7. Why didn&amp;rsquo;t I shoot on my 7 and why did my 11 get me to shoot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;chilling.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Chilling&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It goes back to another topic that comes up time and again with cameras. Is it a joy to shoot? The reason people shoot film, or spend thousands on lenses, or buy point and shoots when their big cameras would shoot better, is because they like shooting with that gear. If you enjoy taking pictures, you&amp;rsquo;ll take more picture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The iPhone 7 was not a joy to shoot on. At one point is was a great camera. But that phone is now 4 years old. The processor is showing its age and it wasn&amp;rsquo;t seamless to take pictures. The screen wasn&amp;rsquo;t anything to write home about. There were some shots that came out great, but the limitations of the camera made it so I felt like I missed more shots than I took. Tracking pictures felt like a chore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But now I got the iPhone 11. And it&amp;rsquo;s a hell of a difference. The camera is a joy to shoot. Having the extra wide angle lens opens so many shots up to me. And I feel like I&amp;rsquo;m working with the strengths of the camera, not against its limitations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;construction.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Construction&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part of the joy of taking pictures for me is the edit process, believe it or not. Going through photos, finding the great shots in between all the trash, and making them shine just fills me so much. But on the iPhone 7, the screen was small enough and my eyes bad enough that I never wanted to edit on there. And by the time I was on my desktop or laptop, the photos never made their way into Lightroom and never got done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two things have changed that for me. One being the new nicer screen. The other being finding Darkroom, a phenomenal Lightroom alternative that works with iCloud. It&amp;rsquo;s nice to be able to walk around, take pictures, and edit the pictures while stopping for coffee. The immediacy of taking a picture, and being able to edit it on phone to show its true potential is so huge for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-strange-turn-in-life&#34;&gt;A Strange Turn in Life&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, gear isn&amp;rsquo;t the only thing that matters. I could have gotten any piece of camera gear that could have revived my love for photos right now. And if I would have gotten this phone six months ago, I doubt I&amp;rsquo;d have gotten back into photography. So what changed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know. A lot and nothing at all? It&amp;rsquo;s hard to say.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;emptyroad.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Empty Road&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mean, it&amp;rsquo;s hard to talk about anything happening in 2020 without talking about the pandemic. I loved going out and discovering new things. Odds are if you&amp;rsquo;re reading this and know me you know I have a band. My band was playing gigs essentially monthly. I had a full life and was starting to be happy. Then &lt;em&gt;pandemic&lt;/em&gt;. And after 6+ months locked up, I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten to appreciating my experiences, and now have a deep need to document it all because I now know how fragile the whole thing really was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On top of that, I played &amp;ldquo;Life is Strange&amp;rdquo; and it brought me back to when I considered myself a photographer, when I most cared. It was my freshmen year of college, I was in dorms alone for the first time in my life and I didn&amp;rsquo;t have a direction that I was certain in. And I remembered that feeling of looking through a viewfinder and in a way finding myself every time, how that helped me then. And how I really need that help now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;kiah.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Kiah&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And I have a supportive partner. The most supportive partner when it comes to hobbies. And that opened my eyes to why I quit before. When I was last taking pictures, I honestly had no one to share the hobby with. I had one person who also liked photography, but they ended up believing their way of shooting was the &amp;ldquo;right&amp;rdquo; way and would belittle my photos to the point where I genuinely started having anxiety using my camera around them. But this person is in the past, and I&amp;rsquo;m working to make sure they don&amp;rsquo;t affect me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And honestly, having someone believe in what you&amp;rsquo;re doing matters a lot. Being an artist can get lonely. It&amp;rsquo;s hard to talk about your hobbies when people don&amp;rsquo;t see things the way you do. Everyone has a phone in their pockets with a good camera. But most people don&amp;rsquo;t think of their shots past putting the subject in the middle of the frame. People aren&amp;rsquo;t into photography like they&amp;rsquo;re into music, they won&amp;rsquo;t talk about their favorite photog like they will their favorite artist, even though most people nowadays take pics daily. Forget things like lenses and &lt;em&gt;f&lt;/em&gt;-stops and lenses. Peoples eyes glaze over the moment that comes up. That gap can make being a photographer hard. Having someone you can share your photos with ends up completely opening up the he world of photography.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;going-out-to-shoot&#34;&gt;Going out to Shoot&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;trespass.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;No Trespassing&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what now. I wrote a ton of words about liking taking pictures. But anyone can write words on the internet. Some people even make money through writing words on the internet. For the first time in like 5 years, I went out just to shoot. But one shoot doesn&amp;rsquo;t make me a photographer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every picture in this blog post was shot on my iPhone 11 and edited in Darkroom (except the pics of the iPhone 11, taken on an iPhone 10). And I am setting myself a goal to photograph and post something interesting once a week. I don&amp;rsquo;t know how much I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to &lt;em&gt;because pandemic&lt;/em&gt; but it&amp;rsquo;s a start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;walkaway.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Moving On&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m also planning on digging up my Yashica Electro 35 film camera and my Olympus Micro 4/3 camera. As much as I love shooting on my phone, having a dedicated camera is a different experience and one I love. I want to develop film and explore aspects of photography I never got to. I never took portraits. I never just walked around an urban area to do pure street photography. I never sat and took a proper landscapes. I have so much room to explore in photography.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found that sense of adventure again. And I&amp;rsquo;m going to do my best to never lose it again.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
