<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pages on Critical Point</title>
    <link>https://zaza.studio/page/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pages on Critical Point</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://zaza.studio/page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Links and Resources</title>
      <link>https://zaza.studio/links-and-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zaza.studio/links-and-resources/</guid>
      <description>A lot of blogs have a quick list of things they like. Well, here are the things I like. If you like me, or my content, or you want to know how my brain got to how it is, here you go.
At the risk of repeating myself, this blog runs off Github Pages, a free webhost (well, HTML host) ran by GitHub; is written primarily in Markdown, a markup language designed as a text-to-HTML tool but that has become the primary note taking and documentation format for so many, and is the default for GitHub; generated by Jekyll, a Ruby based static HTML site generator, and the theme is Minimal Mistakes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Archives</title>
      <link>https://zaza.studio/archives/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zaza.studio/archives/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://zaza.studio/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zaza.studio/about/</guid>
      <description>Playing at the Whisky  I&amp;rsquo;m Emma Medina and this is my bog. I am a non-binary musician, podcaster, and audio editor out of Southern California.
I am the current bassist and former drummer for Unstoppable Force and you can hear my playing bass on the EP Momentum and drums on the semi-live album Appropriate for Distribution. Besides that, you can catch Unstoppable Force playing around the Greater LA Metropolitan area, including frequent venues like the Whisky a Go Go, Malones, the Doll Hut, Chain Reaction, and more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://zaza.studio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zaza.studio/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search</title>
      <link>https://zaza.studio/search/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zaza.studio/search/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
